<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="">
  <channel>
    <title>Zinzy Waleson Geene - RSS</title>
    <description>This is a quiet street on the Internet, a place for soft stances, lived experiences, and critical notes on the things I hold dear.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <language></language>
    <copyright>http://localhost:4000/colophon/#copyright</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 46: Osama</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <ul>
  <li>I’m making an attempt this week to make my weeknotes more of a personal record rather than a performance of how exciting my week is. What I’ve written answers the question I might ask myself seven years from now: what was life like this week?</li>
  <li>I went on the road for on-site research on Tuesday, and was delighted by the particular nursing home that we visited. It seems many Dutch healthcare organizations have understood that environments that resemble the real-life environments of patients contribute to their overall wellbeing. The various spaces we saw were tailored to what life must have been like when the elderly clients were younger: a fifties barber shop, a diner-like restaurant. It was endearing. More professionally, I continue to be stunned by the working lives of people in healthcare. Having to balance tight budgets and strict schedules on the one hand and genuinely wanting the best for clients on the other is not an easy feat.</li>
  <li>It seems like I did pick up Covid while there.</li>
  <li>I’ve begun watching <em>Monarch: Legacy of Monsters</em> and I love my life. The farther I become removed from the humanities major version of myself, the easier it becomes to admit I love monster disaster stories.</li>
  <li>I’ve also begun watching the second season of <em>The Morning Show</em>, and two episodes in I understand why Anja urged me to really, <em>really</em> give it a try. Reese Witherspoon making out with Julianna Margulies is not the stuff of dreams I thought I needed, but here we are. Acting, storyline etc. also good.</li>
  <li>The Israel-Hamas War continues to rage, which has begun to feel like a weird name for the conflict. I wonder what it means that, when I Google those words, the Wikipedia entry to which I’m directed is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2023_Hamas_attack_on_Israel">
2023 Hamas attack on Israel</a>.</li>
  <li>I will never have first-hand experience of what it means to be a Jewish person in the world today, although I’ve been having a second-hand experience that has been leaving me… perturbed. When people discover my partner is Jewish, the tone of the conversation shifts. Not in a pro-Palestinian way, but in the way Jenna Maroney felt the urge to touch Liz Lemon’s hand after learning that Liz had met Oprah on a flight (which, of course, turned out to be a random Black woman).</li>
  <li>While I tested negative, I did spend Friday evening and night in bed with a fever and a body that felt as though it had been hit by a truck. Anja did test positive on Sunday, and so now we’re quarantining. March 2020 all over again.</li>
  <li>I keep thinking a lot about Osama Bin Laden. About the lack of context given by the journalist who shared parts of his <em>Letter to the American people</em> on social media. How TikTok and X, at least for a moment, were rife with people who were barely born when 9/11 happened, proclaiming support for Bin Laden because he had pro-Palestinian things to say. About the importance of digital literacy in the classroom.</li>
  <li>Whenever I’m ill, I bake or cook. I feel bad not doing anything and lying in bed all day, and following a recipe always seems like a good way to pass the time. This week, I made apple crumble custard <em>vlaai</em>. You can take the girl out of Limburg (and thank God for that), but…</li>
</ul>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 09:16:15 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/11/19/week-46</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/11/19/week-46</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Israel-hamas war</category>
        
          <category>Osama bin laden</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The artificial borders of climate activism</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p>Yesterday at the Climate March, someone shouted <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/From_the_river_to_the_sea#Criticism">“From the river to the sea, Palestine will be free”</a>. It was an unfortunate thing. A clean example of the climate changing instantaneously among 85,000 activists.</p>

<p>I was there for four reasons:</p>
<ol>
  <li>My definition of God is “science is indescribably beautiful and we must respect her”</li>
  <li>I can’t think of a more regrettable waste of tax money than having to spend it on health issues we can prevent if only we take better care of our environment</li>
  <li>I have a weak spot for an activist friend, who, through stealth influencing, had instilled in me a deep sense of FOMO about the event</li>
  <li>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carnival_in_the_Netherlands">Dutch carnival season</a> had kicked off on November 11, and I was in the mood for a parade</li>
</ol>

<p>The phrase was understandable coming from the Palestinian woman. Still, I appreciate that its most vicious context of use taints it so ferociously with antisemitism that deploying it as a vehicle for unity is a recipe for disaster. The crowd was so immense that it took hours of dancing in place before we even got started on the route. By the time we got to Museum Square, the words had already left the woman’s mouth.</p>

<p>We got there just in time to watch Greta Thunberg, who had been marching with us, turning her face away from cameras to remind us of why she was there. In between her on the stage and us on the field there were three screens, each projecting her face from a distance. I <em>believe</em> she was there, but the crowd was too big to say anything with much certainty.</p>

<p>My activist friend is one of those rare white people: privileged enough to belong to the 1% of a <em>variety</em> of subgroups, yet so antiracist it brings a tear to your eye. A seeker of nuance and complexity. A political unicorn. As we stood in the longest line I had ever seen, sharing the weight of a “THE CRISIS IS NOW” banner, I said to her: “it’s so… White here.” “Yes,” she said, mildly embarrassed it seemed, “it’s actually a huge problem for us that we could use some help with.”</p>

<p>Growing up in the Dutch South, there was a peculiar detail to the way I engaged with other people of color. I didn’t. There was no nod in the street, no tribe to which I belonged, no “our stories of minority and loneliness resonate”. Color blindness was the tune, and we were dancing to it. After almost a decade in Amsterdam I’ve come to consider this lack of acknowledgement poor behavior. There’s not a black person in the neighborhood I don’t know. I had forgotten my life wasn’t always like this, until yesterday. I counted no more than ten people of color in the crowd, and I exchanged looks with not a single one of them.</p>

<p>Whenever I find myself in a sea of vast whiteness, I ask myself: “where am I, why are there no other people of color here, and should I <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt5052448/"><em>Get Out</em></a>?” Don’t get me wrong, I love white people. <a href="https://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/SomeOfMyBestFriendsAreX">Some of my best friends are white people.</a> My <em>wife</em> is a white person. Consider it a habit I’ve developed growing up in the Netherlands, where nothing about ethnicity is quite as it seems.</p>

<p>What solidifies Greta Thunberg’s identity as a Zoomer is the radical solidarity she and her contemporaries practice, seemingly without effort. Once she finally got on stage, her first act of compassion was to return the word to the Palestinian woman whose sound had been disconnected immediately after she had said the phrase.</p>

<p>What followed is what you may expect to happen when a person traumatized by an active war has to find it in herself to pick up where she left off to tell 85,000 mostly white faces how climate justice and justice for Palestine can exist on the same stage.</p>

<p>It was <em>mayhem</em>.</p>

<p>Once Greta had the mic again, she decided to keep her speech brief, much to the dismay I’m sure of all the people who felt blessed to share a moment in Amsterdam with her. Not <em>so</em> brief, however, that a man couldn’t walk on stage and declare he was there for the climate and not for politics.</p>

<p>The respectability politics are vile today. All I can think about is the power of the speech that could have been. The one in which a Palestinian woman addresses a vast sea of white faces who all listen intently to her talk about climate change. The way she says the words “river” and “sea” only when referring to natural bodies of water. The way she captivates her audience until the very end, when she pulls a Hannah Gadsby to remind us all of the hypocrisy and dangers of compartmental solidarity. The way she nods quietly to the upcoming elections.</p>

<p>The respectability politics are vile today. March-induced feelings of disappointment, uninspired virtue signalling, and racism find each other. A discombobulated display of on-stage pain and the very notion of pro-Palestinian sentiment have quickly been conflated into a rhetoric with which I feel increasingly uncomfortable: that people in power decide when minorities speak about their place in the world. That, when we talk about climate justice, every other topic must give way. That, when we march for a cause that seems to predominantly attract white people, unwritten rules of radical inclusion don’t apply. I feel the climate activism community interviewed for a job with me, and as a result I want to burn its résumé.</p>

<p>It makes me sad.</p>

<p>I’m sad because there are people who think climate justice can exist outside of politics. I’m sad because so many people don’t understand that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_personal_is_political">the personal is political</a>. I’m sad because I want to engage in climate activism, but I don’t feel there’s a place for me at the table. I’m sad because, right now, climate activism feels like a Gutmensch hobby. I’m sad for all the people who can’t tell the difference between antisemitism and anti-Israel sentiment. I’m sad for our Uncle Eli from Tel Aviv who is in and out of his bomb shelter all day.</p>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 09:16:15 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/11/13/artificial-borders-of-climate-activism</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/11/13/artificial-borders-of-climate-activism</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Activism</category>
        
          <category>Climate march</category>
        
          <category>Climate justice</category>
        
          <category>Israel-palestine</category>
        
          <category>Intersectionality</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sermon</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><em>I delivered this sermon today at <a href="http://allsaintsamsterdam.church/">All Saints Amsterdam</a>.</em></p>

<p>A few months ago, along with much of humanity, it seemed, I went to see <em>Barbie</em>. Walking out of the theatre and forming an opinion on this intro to feminism, I renamed the film to a title which I will use again today: “Blueprints: a pamphlet against simplicity”.</p>

<p>It’s nice to see all of your faces here today. I’ve met most of you before, but let me make an official introduction. My name is Zinzy, I’m 35 years old, I live in Amsterdam, and I work in the tech industry. I’m an interaction designer at a medical technology company, which is to say that I design the ways in which doctors and nurses interact with my company’s software. My job is to find out how we can improve the lives of essential workers. It involves a lot of research, empathizing, and imagining. The phrase I repeat over and over again is: “How might we…?”</p>

<p>When people ask me how I came to have such a cool job, I always tell them about my degree in Comparative Literature, and the time I spent studying Theology. It never fails to throw them off. After all, what could be further apart than the literary canon and the abracadabra I do at work all day?</p>

<p>When it comes down to it, really, I just love a good story. I love looking at the ways in which we attempt to make sense of the world around us as well as the world within us. I like stories because of what they say about us. I like stories because we use them in our attempts to humanize others. The truest and sweetest opinion I have on humans is that we are storytelling animals.</p>

<p>When we tell a story, we take a reality (fictional or non-fictional), weave together its most important events and actors, and have our audience look at them through the eyes of one or more entities. To tell a story is an act of selection, of extraction from the truth what we deem important. To tell a story is to curate reality. To tell a story is to shape the world. We turn something complex into vehicles for education, entertainment, action. We abstract from <em>what is</em>, so our shared language is easy to comprehend.</p>

<p>Let me give you an example. Here are two stories about Jesus. One. God has a Son who is also God, he is perfect, and we will never be as good as him, but let’s try. Two. There was a baby born in humility, who grew up to be an inspiration to billions. He was murdered because people thought he was evil, but we never forgot his name. Two stories that invoke entirely different responses. Two stories that remind us that the storyteller is the one who holds the power.</p>

<p>Today, the story we’re telling each other is that of Christian saints. When Mpho suggested I preach about this, my thought process brought me from Mother Teresa via “oh-oh, I am certainly going to screw this up” to the most important commandment in the tech industry: ask why before you ask how.</p>

<p>Before we dive in, let me tell you what I <em>can’t</em> do today. I can’t do is tell you how I think reliving the stories of saints will get us into the Kingdom of Heaven. I can’t even tell you about my favorite saint, because I don’t have one. What I <em>can</em> do is share with you what I have: questions. Questions about questions. Questions about stories. Lots and lots of questions. Today, I hold onto what I know, how to build successful technology, to wade into what I don’t.</p>

<p>Saints. “These are the ones coming out of great tribulation” the lessons tell us. Throughout the centuries, first informally and locally, and then because Popes began restricting to themselves the right to canonize, we’ve collected hundreds upon hundreds of saints. Apostles, martyrs, confessors. Human beings who were perceived to have an exceptional degree of holiness, likeness, or closeness to God.</p>

<p>And today, still, many of us find inspiration in the stories about these people. They’re exemplary models, extraordinary teachers, wonder workers. They’re intercessors through whom we pray. Their stories are designed to inspire us into devotion, into serving God day and night in God’s temple, which is the world. When I think of it, saints <em>are</em> stories. After all, we never get the full picture, just what we’ve chosen is relevant enough to repeat.</p>

<p>These stories fall perfectly in step with the rhythm of Christianity, the rhythm of the Western world. The rhythm of looking for what we could have and could be. What we don’t have, and what we are not. Yet. We live in a culture of becoming. A culture, and a religion, of harder, better, faster, stronger. A culture of progression. Saints were designed to propel us towards the next best thing.</p>

<p>I’m no different from the culture in which I grew up: I love progress. I love growth, I love my learner’s mentality. I love that we use the saintly canon, a set of stories we’ve chosen to prioritize, to be better tomorrow than we are today. But there’s a flip side.</p>

<p>I struggle.</p>

<p>I struggle with saints, with how our tradition has curated, abstracted their human realities. I struggle with the fact that this is an effect of storytelling <em>at all</em>. I struggle with what happens when details go missing, when nuance is lost. I struggle with how, without details and nuance, we idealize as quickly as we devalue. The absence of details turn excellent <em>Harry Potter</em> books into pretty ok <em>Harry Potter</em> movies. It turns Mary Teresa, a sweet, charitable nun with questionable opinions on the realities of sexual violence in the Catholic church, into the pinnacle of female selflessness. It turns inhabitants of Gaza into terrorists. It turns Judaism into the root of all evil.</p>

<p>The art of storytelling is a sharp, double-edged sword. And I want to learn how to handle it more carefully, both as a speaker and as a listener.</p>

<p>I struggle with how stories about saints make us compare our insides to other people’s outsides. Even the word “saint” itself doesn’t necessarily invoke an atmosphere of reaching for the attainable. I struggle with this the same way I struggle with Beyoncé, who, at 23, won her first Grammy, an age at which I took five weeks to find the best typeface for my bachelor thesis.</p>

<p>I struggle with how I can’t see myself in the saints. And I need to see myself in someone to learn from them. As a queer person of color, I am intimately familiar with what it means when I can’t see myself in people. It invokes a sense of otherness, not a sense of community and hope. Color me a Christian millennial, but I learn from <em>mistakes</em>, not from other people’s highlight reels.</p>

<p>I know that, when it comes to the differences between veneration, adoration, admiration, idolatry, and worship, the Catechism of the Catholic Church will tell you I’m doing it wrong. I think that’s just her modus operandi. I don’t think I’m doing it wrong. I think there’s a flaw in the interaction design of how we’ve been taught to grow.</p>

<p>The lesson is this: you are not enough, other people are, and you should feel inspired to be more like them. Inspired by Jesus, Mother Teresa, St. Augustine, Beyonce, Stephen Hawking, Barbie, the Barbie, the resistance fighters. I don’t need a superhuman who can show me how to become more like them. I need a lifetime of flaws to remind me how to be a better me because someone else became a better them.</p>

<p>As a designer, I will forever defend the right of a design flaw to exist. In fact, if we ignore the design flaw, we’ll never be able to make things better. We must look at the problem before we come up with a solution. We must ask why before we ask how.</p>

<p>Why <em>might</em> we become better? And then:</p>

<p><em>How</em> might we use stories in a way that retains our individuality, our dignity, and leaves a margin for error, and room for doubt? How might we let the saints, all the names in the Bible, the very humans they were, inspire us to see ourselves in each other without concluding that we fail to imitate the blueprint?</p>

<p>How might we become better co-humans so that the Kingdom of Heaven is what we refer to when we say “wow, that was a really happy moment for me”? How might we do unto others as we would have them do unto us? How might we remember that <em>that</em> is the entire law, and the rest is just commentary?</p>

<p>Amen.</p>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/11/05/sermon</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/11/05/sermon</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Sermon</category>
        
          <category>Scripture reflection</category>
        
          <category>All saints' day</category>
        
          <category>All saints amsterdam</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 39: Small escapes</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <ul>
  <li>First of all: not a great week. I continue to struggle to notice when I feel stresed or overwhelmed, and it never fails to result in my body giving me a clear sign. On Monday evening, in the midst of a busy work month, my body said “SIT. DOWN.” I needed undtil well into the weekend to feel myself again.</li>
  <li>One of the signs my body knows to give it a very mild version of conversion disorder: I lose the ability to listen to a conversation while I walk without feeling very dizzy. Isn’t the body a beautiful, very annoying, but magnificent thing?</li>
  <li>I start back up at work on Thursday, working the mornings until the weekend. It’s good to acknowledge things aren’t great., It brings clarity and rest.</li>
  <li>On Friday evening <a href="/2023/09/30/film-club-s01e01">I attend the first edition</a> of a new local film club I joined. It confirms what I already know: I love the horror genre, and I love discussing cinema with people who didn’t finish film school Anja I’m looking at you.</li>
  <li>Ever since we <a href="/2023/08/17/norway-et-al">visited Hija de Sanchez in Copenhagen</a> Anja and I have gotten really into Mexican food. By now, I’m so well-versed in the art of a simple-but-sublime taco, that I whip up a delicious meal. Who knew tacos required so little filling?</li>
  <li>On Saturday, I visit Micropia, a zoo-adjacent museum about microbes. I expect to be queasy throughout the entire visit, terrified by the unfortunate-looking mini animals that live in and on every part of my body. Instead, I’m amazed by the beauty of nature. During the mini class I ask a question about algae: if their bodies move towards light and they’re under a microscope for a while, where light comes from all sides, what happens to their health? The laboratory assistant tells me the museum swaps petri dishes regularly so that the algea don’t die. What happens before death, though, I wonder.</li>
  <li>On Sunday, Chenelva comes over for afternoon drinks. She’s one of those rare people: an instant connection and plenty of common ground to grow out friendship on. We marvel at how little we know about queer BIPOC Amsterdam.</li>
  <li>We’ve completed the first season of the Dutch reality show “B&amp;B vol liefde”, in which B&amp;B owners invite four dates into their home. Hate-watching reality television with Anja is one of my favorite pastimes.</li>
</ul>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/10/01/week-39</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/10/01/week-39</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Health</category>
        
          <category>Friendship</category>
        
          <category>Food</category>
        
          <category>Museum</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Film club S01E01</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p>Yesterday, I attended the very first gathering of FC de Filmfanaten, a brand-new film club that my friend Jolien started. There were four of us, and we discussed the movie I was proud to have suggested: <em><span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Talk To Me  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span></em>. I love speaking about films with others, and particularly with this diverse group of people. Everyone brought a completely unique perspective to the film, one brought film industry insights while the other had thoughtful ideas that I hadn’t considered.</p>

<p>Below are the notes I took (in Dutch).</p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/v1696058374/FC_de_Filmfanaten_aflevering_1_-_1_eofyos.jpg" alt="A stylistic illustration of the cover of the movie 'Talk To Me', with a banner for the film club" class="border border-gray-200 dark:border-gray-700" />
<img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/v1696058379/FC_de_Filmfanaten_aflevering_1_-_2_lagm9a.jpg" alt="Impressions and associations we had as a result of watching the movie" class="border border-gray-200 dark:border-gray-700" />
<img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/v1696058374/FC_de_Filmfanaten_aflevering_1_-_3_n6yio4.jpg" alt="Our combined rating and feedback" class="border border-gray-200 dark:border-gray-700" /></p>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 09:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/09/30/film-club-s01e01</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/09/30/film-club-s01e01</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Cinema</category>
        
          <category>Film club</category>
        
          <category>Community</category>
        
          <category>Gathering</category>
        
          <category>Horror</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 37: Rosh Hashanah</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <ul>
  <li>Cooler temperatures! After the hottest week I’ve experienced in months, things were back to comfortable Summer weather. By the time I’m writing this the sky is gray and it’s raining, but this week’s weather was cheerful and moderate.</li>
  <li>On Tuesday and Wednesday I gave two big UX workshops at week to help coworkers understand how they can use UX in their daily work. I’ve been giving workshops for well over a decade, always trusting my instinct to figure out what a particular group or context required. At work, though, we have two wonderful scrum masters who are well-versed in the art of facilitation. I learned a <em>lot</em> from their feedback, and saw a hugh jump between the quality of the first day and of the second day.</li>
  <li>I caught up with a special friend on Wednesday, a young woman I met because we were treated for the same health condition. Her life as a Psych major couldn’t be more different from mine, and yet the red threads our lives resemble one another. I’m fortunate to call her my friend.</li>
  <li>I had missed a few weeks in my RSS reader, but I was pleased to see Manuel Moreale’s <em><a href="https://manuelmoreale.com/">People &amp; Blogs</a></em> is off to a good start. To hell with Anja calling me a geek for being into the IndieWeb, I love visiting other people’s websites. I suspect I love reading what they have to say about those websites even more.</li>
  <li>Last week, I had met an amazing couple of lesbians who invited me over for a casual dinner party on Friday. After a particularly challenging week, it was comforting to hear their experiences as people of color in the world today. I’m already looking forward to inviting them to our place.</li>
  <li>On Saturday, Anja and I kicked off the weekend with a spontaneous redesign of our living room. We finally got rid of my desk, which was a Covid-era purchase used for our home office. What remains now is Anja’s bigger desk, which functions as a dining room table that she hates more than I do. The removal of our home office allowed us to place our sofa there, which has giving the living room a significant amount of extra space. The dining room table continues to double as an office whenever we put our ultrawide monitor there. I like <span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  modular living  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span>, and I’m feeling less and less awkward about the way we’re going about it in our house.</li>
  <li>At the end of our cleaning sprint Anja mentioned it was a beautiful day for this accomplishment, since it was Rosh Hashanah. New living room, new beginnings.</li>
  <li>After visiting Anja’s mom in the afternoon, we biked to Kriterion to Watch <span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Oppenheimer (2023)  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span>.</li>
  <li>Much like the last few days, I’m not in the best of states. There’s an old sadness that keeps saying hello, and I’m slowly beginning to think it might be time to get some help with it.</li>
  <li>I’m nearing the end of my journal, and I’m surprised by how unnervous I am by the few pages I have left. In this past, <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2019/7/12/20680004/notebook-journal-finish-strategies">like the rest of the world, as it appears</a>, I had trouble finishing a journal in a relaxed manner. Looking at the first entry, I see I have 29 days left until it’ll have been one year exactly. Hello nerves.</li>
</ul>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 08:49:15 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/09/17/week-37</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/09/17/week-37</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Mental health</category>
        
          <category>Holidays</category>
        
          <category>Home</category>
        
          <category>Indieweb</category>
        
          <category>Films</category>
        
          <category>Diaries</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 36: Homecoming</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <ul>
  <li>IT IS HOT STOP CLIMATE CHANGE NOW. I don’t think I’ve seen hotter days this year than week 36. Getting out of a hot shower and feeling equally wet fifteen minutes later. Lemonade barely wanting to walk outside. The sun beaming so feriously we can’t keep the windows open. Thank you, Jesus, but please make it cooler.</li>
  <li>There’s something sweet about seeing Amsterdam through the eyes of friends from abroad. On Tuesday, I couldn’t have been more excited to welcome my <a href="https://vineandfig.co/">Vine &amp; Fig friends</a> Pickles and Patrick to the city. They’re two Irish Catholic gay men named Patrick, so we try to make it work any way we can.</li>
  <li>I was saddened by the fact that Jacob, Patrick’s husband, couldn’t make it because he had to stay home and help their dog Jude recover from surgery. All week, I felt like we were missing a limb.</li>
  <li>I joined the V&amp;F leadership team in mid 2020, and we’ve been growing a friendship since. The moment I saw them I knew we were going to get along perfectly in real life, too. Finally getting to embrace them felt like to most natural thing in the world.</li>
  <li>Their AirBnb, which is located just off of Vijzelgracht, was absolutely ridiculous. A three-bedroom penthouse overlooking De Pijp, enormous backyard below, include Swedish saunas and swimming pools. This is how the other half lives.</li>
  <li>I made time to hang out with the Patricks every day they were here, which took us to sweet places. I took them to <a href="https://takeichi-ramen.eu/">Takeichi</a>, my favorite ramen place where I always order anything but ramen, and to <a href="https://studio-k.nu/">Studio K</a>, where they met Lemonade, who chewed through her leash in what seemed like a quiet moment.</li>
  <li>On Friday, we went cheese and wine tasting at <a href="https://abrahamkef.nl/vestigingen/proeflokaal/">Abraham Kef in Noord</a>. It reminded me of how much I love cheese. It was the first thing I was able to say after I learned to say “momma”. I want to make my own cheese.</li>
  <li>After dinner at <a href="https://thuskomme.nl/">Thuskomme</a> on Saturday we took silly mugshots with my Polaroid camera.</li>
  <li>It is truly wonderful to spend time with the Patricks, with whom I weave in and out of conversation topics like it’s nobody’s business. One minute we’re talking about sex toys, and the next about the Book of Job. Knowing they were going to be leaving made me cry a little bit, but then I remembered our friendship had survived without physical get-togethers for three years already.</li>
  <li>On Friday, I met with Mpho to chat church business. I’ve been discerning all Summer about how I would want to be involved in the church now that it’s becoming a church plant, and I decided maintaining the website and social media was a commitment I could make.</li>
  <li>On Sunday, All Saints held her homecoming gathering after the Summer break. Kyle Rader, our new minister, was there for the first time. I liked the elder millennial vibe he brings to the service. It was intimate and lovely, although I seriously missed the pianist. After the service, we gathered for a potluck dinner in the bishop’s garden next to the church. I showed the logo ideas I had been working on, to friendly compliments.</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/v1694936600/IMG_5896_clkzw4.jpg" alt="" />
<img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/v1694936602/FullSizeRender_2_mznjqq.jpg" alt="" />
<img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/v1694936600/FullSizeRender_fgwrwq.jpg" alt="" /></p>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 20:21:15 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/09/10/week-36</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/09/10/week-36</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Mental health</category>
        
          <category>Church</category>
        
          <category>Friends</category>
        
          <category>Amsterdam</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Two things true</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p>I saw a guy on Monday that I went on a date with once. It was one of those whimsical dates. We had fish by the sea. It felt like coming home a little bit. I think the world was trying to introduce me to something for which I wasn’t ready yet. Looking back, that date, more than the others, prepared me for Anja. Looking back through butterfly effect glasses, it might as well have been him.</p>

<p>Yesterday wasn’t a great day. They say recovery is a habit and it is. I was feeling quite low about myself. One hour at my friend’s citizenship party and I’d call it a night. Tomorrow would be full of things, too. Then he arrived. Like an old friend entering the scene.</p>

<p>As soon as I head over, we hug, and he begins telling me that he talks about me when he’s teaching storytelling, on an almost weekly basis, eight years on. “It’s when I begin to talk about tension-building” he says, and I laugh loudly, after which he eyebrows “you know what moment I’m talking about, right?” I say yes but I don’t. Back then, I was too drunk to really remember anything with accuracy.</p>

<p>He turns towards to his friends and continues. “I lean in to kiss her, but she rejects me. And I’m so nervous, thinking ‘gosh, did I really misread all the signs?!’” Apparently, then I said these words, which…:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Wait. This is the last moment that you and I have never kissed.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>As he was telling this story, my entire body lit up. Partially turned on, but predominantly struck with delight. Who is that person? Can I have her number? Oh hold on, he’s talking about me.</p>

<p>Two things can be true at once, and for a moment, my experience of myself felt finely in balance. The universe can hold me as the asshole I see in myself, but also as the person whose butterfly wings can make a small change.</p>

<p>I spent the rest of the evening meeting kind strangers. White cis gay men who wanted to join the queer meetup I run, where my friend and I met. Kinfolk, effortlessly introduced as we blew <span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Cat whisper  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span>s at each other.</p>

<p>My friend looked stunning. An impeccable sense of style, a smile larger than the world, a citizenship bigger than we’d ever ask of him. I knew he was suspended mid-air in all sorts of areas of his life, but, looking at him, I suspected he had arrived somewhere long before any of us ever would.</p>

<p>Today, grabbing coffee in the neighborhood, I meet an acquaintance who’s on sabbatical until the end of the year, spending his time taking action lessons, storytelling workshops.  I ask him if he has ever heard of the girl who almost rejected a kiss by the sea and he bursts out laughing.</p>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/09/06/two-things-true</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/09/06/two-things-true</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Storytelling</category>
        
          <category>Old friends</category>
        
          <category>Dating</category>
        
          <category>Mental health</category>
        
          <category>Self-esteem</category>
        
          <category>Expats</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 34: Somerlust</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <ul>
  <li>Met <span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Tim Bleeker  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span> at <span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Somerlust Park  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span> on <span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  2023-08-22|Tuesday  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span>, a get-together that started as “chilling in the park”, and which turned into grabbing a drink at l’Osteria. The venue is not one I can recommend. When requesting a bigger table because more people would be coming, the waiter scoffed at us. Then he closed the red velvet roped entrance. Later, his colleague told me people often just barge into the venue, ignoring waiters’ requests. I couldn’t imagine the type of person that would do this, and then I looked around.</li>
  <li>I still seem to have a pinguecula because of <a href="/2023/07/22/norway-et-al-2023/">the time I spent in an airconditioned car not too long ago</a>, although my eye is far less red than last week. I feel guilty for disgusting any reader with this information, but hey, they’re weeknotes. Long story short, I now have sunglasses.</li>
  <li>Watched <em><span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Hillsong, A megachurch exposed  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span></em>, and learned a lot about how the church has propelled itself into popularity. Knowing how anti-queer the church has always been, I never felt comfortable attending a service in Amsterdam. The early 10s fashion made me feel nostalgic, though.</li>
  <li>Had a lovely workshop at work about effective team work. It was inspiring, educational, and great for a sense of collaboration, not just with my peers, but also with the company’s leadership. It’s wonderful to be a part of a company that walks its talk so enthusiastically.</li>
  <li>I’m struggling to be a good dog mom to Lemonade, seeing Anja’s conduct and training as much more effective and kind. I’ve been working to praise her good behavior more than I punish her mistakes.</li>
  <li>I was off on <span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  2023-08-25|Friday  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span>, and I went to an early-morning showing of <em><span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Talk to Me (2023)  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span></em>, which I’ll most likely do again. A cute retired Amsterdam couple were discussing their elaborate weekend cooking plans, which I found delighting. They proceeded to talk all throughout the movie.</li>
  <li>I tidied <span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Annelie Wambeek  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span>’s house now that she’s coming back from her month abroad. I brought her some eggs, bread, milk, some treats, and flowers, and I made sure to leave the house smelling fresh. I hope it makes her feel good when she comes home tonight.</li>
  <li>I spent Saturday and Sunday <a href="/2023-08-27-12-43-45">tinkering on the website</a>, and feel good about the results.</li>
  <li>I’ve been on the hunt for a good strategy for <span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Bible study  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span> in <span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Obsidian  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span>, and I managed to find a verse-per-file translation of the <span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  King James Bible  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span> on <a href="https://faithbasedproductivity.com/cross-reference-library-obsidian/">FaithBasedProductivity.com</a> that I added to my Obsidian vault. It took a couple of days before the whole thing was properly synced across my devices, which I suspect might be the result of <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/112ynkj/background_sync_on_ios/">Obsidian Sync not be able to perform background syncs</a>. It made me consider switching to iCloud Sync for a second, but honestly I can’t be bothered. I’m keen to see when I’ll actually begin using the 33,613 files that are taking up over 100 mb in my vault.</li>
  <li>I found myself missing church this week. I’m excited for <a class="internal-link" href="/2023/02/12/all-saints-amsterdam">All Saints Amsterdam</a> to start back up again mid-September. I’m curious to see what’s in store for us.</li>
  <li><span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Mark Delany  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span> came over for Lemonade cuddles and dinner on <span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  2023-08-26|Saturday  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span>. I made <span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Tacos  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span>, successfully if I do say so myself, and we had a lovely time catching up and discussing what really matters: the fact that Mark uses the word “taco” as a standard synonym for female genitalia. I’m still laughing.</li>
</ul>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 18:49:15 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/08/27/week-34</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/08/27/week-34</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Lemonade</category>
        
          <category>Teamwork</category>
        
          <category>Horror</category>
        
          <category>Summer</category>
        
          <category>Bible study</category>
        
          <category>Documentaries</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 33: Landing</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <ul>
  <li>The first week back at work is fairly quiet, I even found myself on the verge of boredom at one point. Organically, this makes me feel bad, but I remind myself that weeks before and after holidays tend to have this effect on my life. I tell myself I’m just landing.</li>
  <li>No one can convince me the municipality of Amsterdam <em>isn’t</em> using major construction projects to show tourists how crap the city can be. On Sunday, I go for a long bike ride to Amsterdamse Bos and back, and crossing the Berlagebrug I’m struck by how quiet the street is without cars racing by. I like it.</li>
  <li>I finished watching <em><span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  The Righteous Gemstones  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span></em>, and I miss them already.</li>
  <li>Anja’s still off for the summer, and I’m watching her slowly recover from being my personal chauffeur for two weeks</li>
  <li>The Summer makes me not want to cook. It’s no help that I’m using <a href="https://anneliewambeek.com/">Annelie</a>’s apartment to work while she’s travelling, and that I use the occasion to order poke bowls for lunch. I’m surprised by the quality of <a href="https://pokeperfect.nl/en/amsterdam/linnaeusstraat/">Poke Perfect</a>’s teriyaki chicken bowl, extra edamame.</li>
  <li>I’m reading and enjoying Robin Meyer’s <em><span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Saving Jesus From the Church  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span></em>, a tool to make my interest in <span title="This points to a note, but it is private" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  orthopraxy  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span> more tangible.</li>
</ul>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/08/20/week-33</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/08/20/week-33</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Food</category>
        
          <category>Amsterdam</category>
        
          <category>Summer</category>
        
          <category>Reading</category>
        
          <category>Theology</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>