<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="">
  <channel>
    <title>Zinzy Waleson Geene - RSS</title>
    <description>This is a quiet street on the Internet, a place for soft stances, lived experiences, and critical notes on the things I hold dear.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <language></language>
    <copyright>http://localhost:4000/colophon/#copyright</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 34: Assumptions</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 11:11:15 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/09/03/week-35/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/09/03/week-35/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Lemonade</category>
        
          <category>Friends</category>
        
          <category>Theatre</category>
        
          <category>Ux</category>
        
          <category>Workshops</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 34: Somerlust</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <ul>
  <li>Met <span title="This note is not for public consumption (yet)" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Tim Bleeker  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span> at <span title="This note is not for public consumption (yet)" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Somerlust Park  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span> on <span title="This note is not for public consumption (yet)" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  2023-08-22|Tuesday  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span>, a get-together that started as “chilling in the park”, and which turned into grabbing a drink at l’Osteria. The venue is not one I can recommend. When requesting a bigger table because more people would be coming, the waiter scoffed at us. Then he closed the red velvet roped entrance. Later, his colleague told me people often just barge into the venue, ignoring waiters’ requests. I couldn’t imagine the type of person that would do this, and then I looked around.</li>
  <li>I still seem to have a pinguecula because of <a href="/2023/07/22/norway-et-al-2023/">the time I spent in an airconditioned car not too long ago</a>, although my eye is far less red than last week. I feel guilty for disgusting any reader with this information, but hey, they’re weeknotes. Long story short, I now have sunglasses.</li>
  <li>Watched <em><span title="This note is not for public consumption (yet)" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Hillsong, A megachurch exposed  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span></em>, and learned a lot about how the church has propelled itself into popularity. Knowing how anti-queer the church has always been, I never felt comfortable attending a service in Amsterdam. The early 10s fashion made me feel nostalgic, though.</li>
  <li>Had a lovely workshop at work about effective team work. It was inspiring, educational, and great for a sense of collaboration, not just with my peers, but also with the company’s leadership. It’s wonderful to be a part of a company that walks its talk so enthusiastically.</li>
  <li>I’m struggling to be a good dog mom to Lemonade, seeing Anja’s conduct and training as much more effective and kind. I’ve been working to praise her good behavior more than I punish her mistakes.</li>
  <li>I was off on <span title="This note is not for public consumption (yet)" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  2023-08-25|Friday  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span>, and I went to an early-morning showing of <em><a class="internal-link" href="/talk-to-me-2023">Talk to Me (2023)</a></em>, which I’ll most likely do again. A cute retired Amsterdam couple were discussing their elaborate weekend cooking plans, which I found delighting. They proceeded to talk all throughout the movie.</li>
  <li>I tidied <span title="This note is not for public consumption (yet)" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Annelie Wambeek  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span>’s house now that she’s coming back from her month abroad. I brought her some eggs, bread, milk, some treats, and flowers, and I made sure to leave the house smelling fresh. I hope it makes her feel good when she comes home tonight.</li>
  <li>I spent Saturday and Sunday <a href="/2023-08-27-12-43-45">tinkering on the website</a>, and feel good about the results.</li>
  <li>I’ve been on the hunt for a good strategy for <span title="This note is not for public consumption (yet)" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Bible study  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span> in <span title="This note is not for public consumption (yet)" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Obsidian  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span>, and I managed to find a verse-per-file translation of the <span title="This note is not for public consumption (yet)" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  King James Bible  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span> on <a href="https://faithbasedproductivity.com/cross-reference-library-obsidian/">FaithBasedProductivity.com</a> that I added to my Obsidian vault. It took a couple of days before the whole thing was properly synced across my devices, which I suspect might be the result of <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/112ynkj/background_sync_on_ios/">Obsidian Sync not be able to perform background syncs</a>. It made me consider switching to iCloud Sync for a second, but honestly I can’t be bothered. I’m keen to see when I’ll actually begin using the 33,613 files that are taking up over 100 mb in my vault.</li>
  <li>I found myself missing church this week. I’m excited for <a class="internal-link" href="/2023/02/12/all-saints-amsterdam/">All Saints Amsterdam</a> to start back up again mid-September. I’m curious to see what’s in store for us.</li>
  <li><span title="This note is not for public consumption (yet)" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Mark Delany  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span> came over for Lemonade cuddles and dinner on <span title="This note is not for public consumption (yet)" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  2023-08-26|Saturday  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span>. I made <a class="internal-link" href="/tacos">Tacos</a>, successfully if I do say so myself, and we had a lovely time catching up and discussing what really matters: the fact that Mark uses the word “taco” as a standard synonym for female genitalia. I’m still laughing.</li>
</ul>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 18:49:15 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/08/27/week-34/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/08/27/week-34/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Lemonade</category>
        
          <category>Teamwork</category>
        
          <category>Horror</category>
        
          <category>Summer</category>
        
          <category>Bible study</category>
        
          <category>Documentaries</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 33: Landing</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <ul>
  <li>The first week back at work is fairly quiet, I even found myself on the verge of boredom at one point. Organically, this makes me feel bad, but I remind myself that weeks before and after holidays tend to have this effect on my life. I tell myself I’m just landing.</li>
  <li>No one can convince me the municipality of Amsterdam <em>isn’t</em> using major construction projects to show tourists how crap the city can be. On Sunday, I go for a long bike ride to Amsterdamse Bos and back, and crossing the Berlagebrug I’m struck by how quiet the street is without cars racing by. I like it.</li>
  <li>I finished watching <em><span title="This note is not for public consumption (yet)" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  The Righteous Gemstones  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span></em>, and I miss them already.</li>
  <li>Anja’s still off for the summer, and I’m watching her slowly recover from being my personal chauffeur for two weeks</li>
  <li>The Summer makes me not want to cook. It’s no help that I’m using <a href="https://anneliewambeek.com/">Annelie</a>’s apartment to work while she’s travelling, and that I use the occasion to order poke bowls for lunch. I’m surprised by the quality of <a href="https://pokeperfect.nl/en/amsterdam/linnaeusstraat/">Poke Perfect</a>’s teriyaki chicken bowl, extra edamame.</li>
  <li>I’m reading and enjoying Robin Meyer’s <em><span title="This note is not for public consumption (yet)" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Saving Jesus From the Church  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span></em>, a tool to make my interest in <span title="This note is not for public consumption (yet)" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  orthopraxy  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span> more tangible.</li>
</ul>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/08/20/week-33/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/08/20/week-33/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Food</category>
        
          <category>Amsterdam</category>
        
          <category>Summer</category>
        
          <category>Reading</category>
        
          <category>Theology</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Norway et al</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_1400/v1692260659/IMG_4735_mxgbxc.jpg" /></p>

<p>After two weeks in Scandinavia, it’s clear: we are both too Dutch for proper recycling. Secretly hoarding our trash to avoid a reprimanding from our AirBnb host as he hovers over his six-compartment recycling bin, we continue our trip from rural Sweden to Copenhagen looking for a public recycling station.</p>

<p>“Imagine if we got so nervous about doing it wrong that we ended up just dumping these bags by the roadside” I say to Anja.</p>

<p>“Last Tuesday, two Dutch lesbians were found dead just outside of Lidköping after the Swedish environmental police task force shot them at point-blank range for abusing the recycling system. Their families have been notified, begrudgingly.” Anja jokes, staring off into the distance.</p>

<p>“Not <em>Queen &amp; Slim</em>, but King &amp; Thicc!”, I suggest, “You can be King”.</p>

<p>“But I’m thicc, too”, Anja complains.</p>

<p>By now, we’re home again, back from our first proper vacation in four years, and boy oh boy, did we need it.</p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,h_1400/v1692260665/IMG_5143_zgqdss.jpg" /></p>

<p>Our plan was simple: make Anja’s dream come true by renting a Tesla, drive it to Norway, do nothing there for a week, and then spend another week slowly making our way back via the Swedish countryside, and Copenhagen, where our friends live.</p>

<p>After two long, well-airconditioned days in our wonderful car we made it to Eastern Norway. In Hallingdal, one of the country’s most popular ski destinations, we found a beautiful and cozy cabin on top of a mountain, overlooking the Tisleifjorden. To our surprise, it proved the perfect getaway for people who didn’t really want to… <em>do</em> anything.</p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_1400/v1692260664/IMG_4771_w0rdef.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_1400/v1692260657/IMG_4764_wegskx.jpg" /></p>

<p>It’s indeed exquisite, the Norwegian faith in our human ability to treat nature with respect. Quietly, it makes an enormous difference. The difference is in the shared understanding of where we leave our trash. It’s in the thousands of cabins spread out across the country, <a href="https://english.dnt.no/">where travellers can stay for next to nothing</a>. It’s in the fire wood left behind in the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/golsfjelletvest/posts/pfbid021q9V7g4XeKd5Wz3QfEbxmsBHWVYmEHEb9mqBT4mn1F34SUCe8LoafcfE6fE61pQBl?locale=nl_NL">freely-accessible <em>grillhytte</em></a>. It’s in the canoe that just lays by the water, available to anyone.</p>

<p>“You don’t even really have to lock your doors”, one fisherman commented while teaching his son to throw a line.</p>

<p>We never kept our doors unlocked, of course. The city is embedded in our system too deeply, as were the countless “cabin in the woods” movie plots I remembered. If anything, though, it helped us pause, listen to the sound of nothing, and listen to our bodies, which were telling us to take that second nap of the day.</p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,h_1400/v1692260657/FullSizeRender_6_wlkfj3.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_1400/v1692260666/IMG_4778_fm3g1i.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,h_1400/v1692260656/FullSizeRender_1_ci1pqv.jpg" /></p>

<p>On Sunday, one day earlier than intended, we swiftly packed the car and drove all night to Lidköping, by Vänern, Sweden’s largest lake. While we’d been napping and relaxing, the world was reading the headlines about Storm Hans, a twice-a-century type of storm that would’ve gotten us stuck on that mountain if we hadn’t left when we did. That three hours of driving through landslide-prone mountains wasn’t going to be pleasant, even in a well-heated Tesla.</p>

<p>The clouds were low as we drove off.</p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_1400/v1692260661/IMG_5247_q6xbsb.jpg" /></p>

<p>Copenhagen, <em>kubnhawn</em> for the in-crowd, was a lot lighter, sunnier, and safer. We stayed with Naomi, Shlomik and little Goldie. Their cute, young family, the house, and the fact that were surrounded by thousands of people everywhere we went, was everything I needed after the quiet Norwegian fjords. One day exploring the city was enough to convince me: I need to visit again.</p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_1400/v1692260654/IMG_5556_zetoqz.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,h_1400/v1692260660/FullSizeRender_24_or4mju.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,h_1400/v1692260655/FullSizeRender_23_zsjphm.jpg" /></p>

<h3 id="some-preliminary-mostly-food-related-highlights-from-two-weeks-in-norway-sweden-and-denmark">Some preliminary (mostly food-related) highlights from two weeks in Norway, Sweden, and Denmark</h3>
<ul>
  <li>So far, not impressed with Norwegian bakeries</li>
  <li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brunost">Brunost</a>, however, is my new favorite snack.</li>
  <li>The quiet atmosphere of the fjords in the Summer months is spectacular. We went days without seeing a person.</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.polarbrod.se/">Polarbröd</a> remains amazing, and next to jubileumskaka I now also love hällakaka</li>
  <li>Sheep are scarier than I thought they would be</li>
  <li>Lemonade appears to possess a strong instinct for herding sheep</li>
  <li>Copenhagen gives hints of The Hague, Berlin, Paris, and Amsterdam</li>
  <li>They weren’t lying about mountain air</li>
  <li>Whatever positive things you’ve heard about Copenhagen’s <a href="https://lovesanchez.com/taquerias">Hija de Sanchez</a> are true</li>
  <li>The Norwegian mountains have Karens just like any other place in the world</li>
  <li>There’s a <a href="https://goo.gl/maps/PGBfQMjaHrvZguP78">gas station in Gol, Norway</a> that sells one of the finest soft-serve ice creams I’ve ever had</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="general-vacation-notes">General vacation notes</h3>
<ul>
  <li>I should get my driver’s license</li>
  <li>An icebox with proper cooling elements can go a long way</li>
  <li>Vacuum-sealed cheese stays fine for at least two weeks (provided you have an icebox)</li>
</ul>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/08/17/norway-et-al/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/08/17/norway-et-al/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Vacation</category>
        
          <category>Scandinavia</category>
        
          <category>Europe</category>
        
          <category>Travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Pride means to me in 2023</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="/2023/04/26/dear-nienke-you-should-have-a-website/">Nienke</a>, Mehdi, an anonymous friend, and I attend the annual Pride March. It’s the city’s first <a href="https://pride.amsterdam/en/pride-foundation/">two-week Pride festival in Amsterdam</a>, each week organized by a different organization. With a naturally intersectional and radically-inclusive interpretation of the term “queer”, I am pleased <a href="https://queer-amsterdam.org/">Queer Amsterdam</a> is taking care of the annual Pride Walk.</p>

<p>On Friday, I tell colleagues over office drinks why we still need Pride. The fact that I had to write “an anonymous friend” instead of the name of a person I love and admire illustrates my point beautifully.</p>

<p>“I think I’ll wear my face mask” he says, 20 minutes into the event. “Am I getting too close?” I ask, concerned. No, he just doesn’t feel comfortable being photographed. The off chance that his parents may see him is not worth it.</p>

<p>As we walk, I think about the meaning of the word “pride”. If we walk in a Pride March, can we be proud without wanting to be photographed and broadcast for anyone to see? A sign in the crowd reads “you can’t be what you can’t see”, and I agree. Representation is crucial, to this my life is a testament. But what burden does that place on people whose visibility is dangerous to themselves?</p>

<p>The intersection of queerdom, the way it interacts with ethnicity, religion, ability, neurodivergence, age, education, and location, is why I’m here today. Why I’m here at all. Mehdi, who has never attended a Pride event in his life, learns to shout along:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>What do we want?<br />
TRANS RIGHTS!<br />
When do we want them?<br />
NOW!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The speeches this year spark my interest. <a href="https://pride.amsterdam/ambassadors/tieneke-sumter/">Tieneke</a> talks about consent, an oft-overlooked point of concern in our queer communities. Someone whose name I forgot talks about bisexuality. I remember how unsettling it was as a young adult that people told me I was “in transit”, on my way to being either gay or straight.</p>

<p>I’m here today shouting for myself, a little bit, but also to engage in the praxis of allyship which is by default an aspirational habit: doing the things we know to be right, without determining for other people whether we can call ourselves their allies.</p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/v1690043403/FullSizeRender_qbh0ze.jpg" alt="A person in a trenchcoat and a hat looks on as a Pride march walks by, photographing the event" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/v1690043396/FullSizeRender_2_alxoze.jpg" alt="A person in a colorful jacket walks in a Pride march" /></p>

<!-- ![](https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/v1690043404/IMG_3947_nmdiap.jpg) -->
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/07/22/pride-walk-2023/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/07/22/pride-walk-2023/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Queerdom</category>
        
          <category>Intersectionality</category>
        
          <category>Pride</category>
        
          <category>Amsterdam</category>
        
          <category>Activism</category>
        
          <category>Friends</category>
        
          <category>Allyship</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The blonde</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p>At the end of the shopping street<br />
for people who look like<br />
they do in the magazines<br />
there’s a blonde marching in place waiting<br />
for the light to turn green.<br />
She is not running per se, rather<br />
she’s hinting at running.<br />
Selling it, the way<br />
Charlize Theron sells<br />
a night to remember in a perfume commercial<br />
with next to nothing for evidence.</p>

<p>Me, a tired mother,<br />
and a tennis player with wet hair<br />
stare at the blonde,<br />
one more covertly than<br />
the others.<br />
I know not to tilt my head<br />
when encounting something<br />
in which the world tells me<br />
I will never see myself.</p>

<p>There are so many things<br />
that are perfect<br />
about the blonde that I<br />
get dizzy counting.<br />
Even a thigh gap as big as hers<br />
wouldn’t be able to hold<br />
all the details.</p>

<p>At this point, the length,<br />
and the waviness, and the glossiness,<br />
and the readiness of her hair<br />
are just a complete unnecessity.</p>

<p>We all hate her, the blonde.<br />
Me, a tired mother,<br />
and a tennis player with wet hair.<br />
We hate her because<br />
of all the little things<br />
the world has denied us<br />
the words to articulate.</p>

<p>We all hate her, the blonde,<br />
and the blonde hates herself<br />
a little, too,<br />
for reasons so bafflingly<br />
unimportant to us<br />
she could die from jealousy.</p>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/07/14/the-blonde/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/07/14/the-blonde/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Poem</category>
        
          <category>Culture</category>
        
          <category>Standpoint</category>
        
          <category>Prejudice</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 27: Haven</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <ul>
  <li>This week, I attended my first Gerimedica party. It’s great to know I can expect a big celebration every year, and not just for the company’s sweet sixteen. It confirmed what I already know: great vibe, great taste, great people.</li>
  <li>I went to Bar Bario on Saturday for a meet-up called Hair Haven, which fosters connection between people with curly hair. Again, I was struck by how welcoming the space is. It’s a ridiculous feeling, being the norm there.</li>
  <li>I’m tired these days. Too much fun, too little rest. I’m better at napping, though. On Sunday, I barely wanted to get out of bed after a little snooze. Three years ago, a nap was unthinkable.</li>
  <li>I’m giving Reni Eddo-Lodge‘s <em>Why I’m No Longer Talking to White People About Race</em> another spin. The title alone makes it a hard read, but I’m hoping I’ll find myself along the way.</li>
  <li>I saw <em>Dalva</em> at Ketelhuis. Reading the reviews, I’m surprised so many people seem to interpret the girl’s dress style as “an adult woman in the 50s”. I thought it was reminiscent of the way girls dressed when the camera first came out. Not a girl, not yet a woman. Regardless, I imagine being Dalva’s mother, getting to know her daughter again, and understanding what has gone so wrong in the fibers of het child. It sends chills down my spine.</li>
  <li>In another childhood trauma narrative, I thought it was so moving that Jan Broberg played the therapist in the Showtime series on her turbulent childhood. I fantasized the scenes functioned as a systemic family constellation, her talking to her childhood self. The reality was probably much more technical than that.</li>
  <li>Anja had a very intense and short stint with <em>Call of Duty</em>, remarking on its evocative storytelling in the Cold War portion. She finished it, though, and the zombies turned om her off with such immediacy that she’s back to NBA.</li>
  <li>After hearing it only once, Billie Eilish’s “The 30th” is stuck in my head. She and her brother have a good thing going.</li>
</ul>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/07/09/week-27/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/07/09/week-27/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Work</category>
        
          <category>Safe spaces</category>
        
          <category>Film</category>
        
          <category>Party</category>
        
          <category>Television</category>
        
          <category>Music</category>
        
          <category>Gaming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 26: Keti Koti</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p>Two months of onboarding have rushed by in a blink. The new job is absolutely wonderful: the people are great, the work is complex and important, and the office itself is perhaps the finest I’ve ever worked at. I joined this company because the challenges they have seemed interesting to me. I’m very pleased that, two months in, it’s difficult to think that, at one point in time, these challenges weren’t also mine. I’ve made the right decision.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, I met two friends with whom I share a special history. The time we spent together resulted in many things. One of them was the tattoo on my left arm that say “WAT ER IS” (“what is there”). Spending my evening with them, sharing a meal, shedding a few tears, reminded me of why the tattoo is there.</p>

<p>On Saturday, Anja and I watched Keti Koti’s <a href="https://ketikotiamsterdam.nl/bigi-spikri-optocht/">Bigi Spikri memorial service</a> on television. I truly detest that the thing we requested became such a point of contention, that finally getting it almost made us forget that what we requested was a minimum viable product. Still, King Willem Alexander offering an apology and asking for forgiveness was history in the making. As an Afropean person I’m easily erased from the Dutch narrative of Trans-Atlantic slave trade that focuses on the Netherlands and her former colonies. Mentioning us by name specifically let Willem Alexander articulate how well he has been listening these past few years.</p>

<p>In the afternoon we made our way to Museumplein for the Keti Koti festival. Upside: I got to eat cotton candy, twice, and we got to financially contribute to many great Black causes in the city. Downside: I spent way too much time in line for food with hundreds of other people.</p>

<p>Reading! I finished a book. I have a track record of struggling to enjoy reading as a burnt-out lit major, but <span title="This note is not for public consumption (yet)" class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span>  Citizen (2015)  <span class="invalid-link-brackets"></span></span> was easy to get through. It turns out I am enthusiast of the lyric essay genre. I picked up a book of poetry by Anton de Kom at Keti Koti, and I’m diving head-first into that.</p>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/07/01/week-26/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/07/01/week-26/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Work</category>
        
          <category>Onboarding</category>
        
          <category>Racism</category>
        
          <category>Trans-atlantic slave trade</category>
        
          <category>Reading</category>
        
          <category>Holidays</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We all live in a white submersible</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p>I love a good media drama. Like a moth to a flame, or perhaps more accurately like a fly to dog poo, I am drawn to it. I check the news multiple times a day. I scoff at outlets that don’t deem it worthy of the front page. I also scoff at outlets that do. A media drama can antagonize me the way Adele disappoints me with her popularity.</p>

<p>The fact that I’m part of a Titanic/<em>Titanic</em>-obsessed gaggle of netizens somehow has me convinced I’m not just procrastinating. Five men with money — sums of it — on their way to Titanic in a little titanium box, are lost at sea. To empathize, the world holds her breath.</p>

<p>Growing up without my father, I never gave much thought to the reality in which he once found himself, well over half a century ago. Ten years old, him and his football team of siblings, on a boat, lost at sea. I wonder if the five men ever saw Titanic. I wonder if they cried.</p>

<p>I imagine he was lost at sea the way only a child can be: cursed with the spirit of adventure. Where did the boat depart from? Did he bring a toy? Was there a tiger? The only way I can read the scene is with the poetry of someone who’ll never know what it’s like to leave home when home is the mouth of a shark.</p>

<p>The Internet continues her wailing. Debris is found. The 19-year-old had only tagged along to make Father’s Day one to remember. I don’t know the story about my father’s father. I never celebrated a proper Father’s Day. My father’s father was long dead before the boat was put out to sea. Yes?</p>

<p>A Dutch news site tells me, at the bottom in small font, about their podcast episode. Who is responsible for the boat refugees who drowned off the Greek coast? Could we leave their bodies on the ocean floor? On Reddit, people share animated maps of the football team of rescue boats circling Titanic.</p>

<p>I love a good media drama. Like a moth to a flame, or perhaps more accurately like a fly to dog poo, I am drawn to it. Like a mosquito it drowns out the other humming. Like a natural disaster it refrigerates the other stories, the puzzles I fear I will never solve.</p>

]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/06/22/we-all-live-in-a-white-submersible/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/06/22/we-all-live-in-a-white-submersible/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>News</category>
        
          <category>Lyric essay</category>
        
          <category>Being black</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dear Nienke, you should have a website</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p>Every time I embark on a journey towards a published post about why it’s good to have a website, I get lost in the reality of personal details. Everyone has different reasons for believing something. Aiming to take them all into account doesn’t help me write anything that feels worthwhile and not like a derivative<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>.</p>

<p>It feels much more relevant to focus my attention on specific people. In this case I’m focusing my attention on you, Nienke. I think you should have a personal website. Let me tell you why.</p>

<p>You should have a personal website not because you need to grow an audience, and turn your hobbyist writing into a profession.</p>

<p>You should have a personal website not because you’re an expert on some subject, and it would be cruel to deny the world your wisdom.</p>

<p>You should have a personal website not because you think you’re important.</p>

<p>You should have a personal website not because the world is in need of your highlight reel.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>You should have a personal website because I think the online world is as real as the offline world. You have a presence in one, and you should have a presence in the other.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Consider your personal website an online living room of sorts. The place that displays, in a variety of ways, who you are, what you care about, and how you’re moving through the world.</p>

<p>You’re free to invite anyone to come in, and have them see anything you deem relevant. They can stay for three seconds and walk out the door, or dwell for a bit, opening drawers, going back in time, answering questions, questioning answers.</p>

<p>Imagine that there are people on the other side of the world who would want to know how you’re doing, what you’re thinking and learning. Not because you’re you, per se, but simply because you have in common the habit of sharing your experiences in an online space where you are the boss.</p>

<p>There is a <em>cozy web</em> out there, where people connect simply because they enjoy snacking on each other’s slices of life: the seemingly unimportant moments, words, images that approximate what it means to be human.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Imagine, also, what it means when I say “you are the boss”.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Think of how little you control about yourself on the Internet. The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">.nl</code> website of your name is already registered, but are you its owner? I doubt it. Your company has a portrait of you on their website, and it’s beautiful, but you can’t add anything to the page it’s on, can you?</p>

<p>You have an updated LinkedIn page and it’s a great way for people to find you, but do you live to work or work to live? Besides, it’s LinkedIn designers who decide for you what your profile will look like. If you’d ever want to do anything other than write a post or update your experiences, you’re out of luck.</p>

<p>There’s an old newsletter containing an interview with you, again with that wonderful portrait. It’s probably because of your work that this is all I can find on you. It makes me sad, Nienke, it does.</p>

<p>You know why? I love learning about what you’re up to. And I suspect the places where you share that are social media profiles that don’t necessarily use your full name. It’s great for privacy, of course, I get it. But I don’t want to be on social media to stay in your loop.</p>

<p>Or rather, I want social media to be our websites. You read mine and I read yours, we write comments on our own websites and they’re posted to each other’s websites automatically.<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> Twitter can fall, Instagram can crumble, LinkedIn can add an expensive subscription model, but you and I will still have our websites.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I want you to take up space on the Internet, Nienke.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I want you to enjoy doing so and perhaps even making new connections in the process. I want you to learn how to build your own website and tell me in a year that it’s actually much easier than you thought. I want you to feel empowered. And to have a <a href="/now">now</a> page, and to keep lists on your websites of things you love in Amsterdam and beyond.</p>

<p>I want you to feel that you can escape the rat race of likes, favs, and reposts. I think what you have to say is worth more than the hipness of some platform.</p>

<p>I want you to fall in love with personal websites so much that you write about it on your website, and tell people about it at Coffee Company.</p>

<p>I want to share with you the wonderful community of random people from all over the world, who are so much more curious and enthusiastic, so genuinely supportive, and so much kinder than any of the communities I’ve ever found on Big Tech platforms.</p>

<p>I want to read what you have to say about the world when you stop worrying what your blog should be called.</p>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>See for example <a href="https://jamesg.blog/2023/04/13/exploring-personal-websites/">James’ neat post on personal sites</a> or, more broadly, <a href="https://indieweb.org/why">the “Why” page on the IndieWeb Wiki</a> <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>On the IndieWeb we call this a <a href="https://indieweb.org/Webmention">“webmention”</a>. <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/26/dear-nienke-you-should-have-a-website/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/04/26/dear-nienke-you-should-have-a-website/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Friends</category>
        
          <category>Indieweb</category>
        
          <category>Personal archiving</category>
        
          <category>Letters</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>