<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="">
  <channel>
    <title>Zinzy Waleson Geene - RSS</title>
    <description>Zinzy Waleson Geene is a researcher, designer, facilitator, and IndieWeb enthusiast from Amsterdam.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <language></language>
    <copyright>http://localhost:4000/colophon/#copyright</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>All Saints Amsterdam</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          <p>She blesses Anja, me, and a handful of other people who carved out time in their Sunday evenings to come to Church. I have never been inside this particular church building before, and chuckle at how <em>new</em> the Old Catholic decor is: in imagery and candle lighting possibilities it’s reminiscent of the average Dutch Roman Catholic church. Its white walls and central heating tell me something different.</p>

          
          <br />
          <html><body>
<p>She blesses Anja, me, and a handful of other people who carved out time in their Sunday evenings to come to Church. I have never been inside this particular church building before, and chuckle at how <em>new</em> the Old Catholic decor is: in imagery and candle lighting possibilities it’s reminiscent of the average Dutch Roman Catholic church. Its white walls and central heating tell me something different.</p>

<p>You may think I chose this church because the woman blessing us is Desmond Tutu’s daughter, the Reverend Canon Mpho Tutu van Furth, and because Anja and I can’t help but fangirl. I’m here because she’s a Black queer person leading a church service that I can attend in person. I never thought I would see the day.</p>

<p>Dare I wonder whether I have found a new church in <a href="https://allsaintsamsterdam.com/" target="_blank">All Saints Amsterdam</a>?</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/02/12/all-saints-amsterdam/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/02/12/all-saints-amsterdam/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Religion</category>
        
          <category>Amsterdam</category>
        
          <category>Queerdom</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Saturday morning routines</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          
          
          <br />
          <html><body>
<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_1000/v1676107091/zinzy.website/IMG_9715_eldt4r.jpg" alt="A pen drawing of a woman and a man reading the newspaper over coffee. The woman is Dutch philosopher Marli Huijer, and I assumed the man to her left is her husband. In the drawing, the husband reads the paper grumpily, as Marli's face shows more curiosity."></p>

<p>Living in a good neighborhood has many advantages. One of them is that it makes me want to spend a lot of time there. Saturday morning is very likely my favorite day in the neighborhood.</p>

<p>I get up, without an alarm, around 6:30, engage in some morning writing, and fanny around the house for a bit. I take a shower at 7:45, and walk to my favorite coffee place at 08:20. Sometimes I wait outside for a few minutes until their doors open at 08:30.</p>

<p>“Medium decaf mocaccino, half cow’s milk, half Tony Chocolonely.” I say it, but none of the baristas need reminding. Sometimes I bring my computer to work on my personal site, sometimes I bring a book and my diary. I’m not the only one who lives Saturday mornings like this.</p>

<p>This morning I hung out, drawing people who were conducting a similar Saturday morning routine. A great start to the weekend.</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/02/11/saturday-morning-routines/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/02/11/saturday-morning-routines/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Diaries</category>
        
          <category>Drawings</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Walking with Annelie</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          
          
          <br />
          <html><body>
<p>Walking with Annelie is coffee indoors today. We’ve told each other we need to go on more walks. She asks if we should dress warmly for the cold, wet park, or if we should just grab a table inside. Normally at this hour, Coffee Company is packed to the brim with digital nomads, so “dress for cold, hope for warmth” I say. Miraculously, there are two tables from which we can choose.</p>

<p>I’m so proud of the work Annelie has been doing, <a href="https://www.anneliewambeek.com/" target="_blank">building a business from scratch</a>, and wrapping her head around how she can do her best work. We discuss productivity; tools, methods, apps, Etsy calendar print-outs. Today, I tell her how much <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@elizabethfilips" target="_blank">Elizabeth Filips</a> has been helping me. We decide we should join <a href="https://www.meetup.com/shutupandwriteamsterdam/" target="_blank">Shut Up &amp; Write</a> sometime.</p>

<p>It was clear from the start to both Anja and I that Annelie would make a great godmother for <a href="http://lemonade.waleson.us/" target="_blank">Lemonade the puppy</a>. We’ve decided to go full over-the-top with anything dog-related, and luckily Annelie is more than happy to review my birth announcement card options. She couldn’t radiate more enthusiasm about this dog if she tried. And she hasn’t even met her yet.</p>

<p>As we shmoozed over coffee, I was reminded of the time when doing this indoors wasn’t even possible. I remember the Coffee Company line going all the way around the block, the overflowing trash bins with paper coffee cups, the increasing amount of fresh air we were all taking in. It’s nice to spend time indoors again, but I do miss the park. I can’t wait for spring to start.</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/02/02/walking-with-annelie/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/02/02/walking-with-annelie/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Walking</category>
        
          <category>Parks</category>
        
          <category>Coffee</category>
        
          <category>Pandemic</category>
        
          <category>Friends</category>
        
          <category>Winter</category>
        
          <category>Productivity</category>
        
          <category>Neurodivergence</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>That was January 2023</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          
          
          <br />
          <html><body>
<p>January flew, <em>flew</em> by, I tell you. We started with “wow, 2023 already, let’s have a chill time this year, hey what’s on Netflix?” and at the time of writing everything is different:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Things are not chill, because we’re preparing ourselves, our lives, and our house for our first-ever puppy</li>
  <li>Both our work lives are unexpectedly bustling and busy</li>
  <li>We cancelled Netflix</li>
</ul>

<p>I’ve been saying for years that I’d be willing to pay 100 euros a month for a single, all-encompassing international streaming platform. I suppose it’s never going to happen, but, hey, at least we’ll have that puppy, right?</p>

<h3 id="the-puppy">The puppy!</h3>
<p>Like I said, we kicked off the year very quietly, thinking “meh, someone asked us if we wanted a puppy, but we’re not really sure just yet.” This all changed ones we learned that eight healthy puppies were born and we were allowed to pick first. <a href="/2023/01/15/sneak-preview/" target="_blank">We went for a visit</a> mid-January, and fell deeply in love with little Lemonade, who’s coming home at the end of February.</p>

<p>I went from a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Dogfree/" target="_blank">serious dog-free advocate</a> to an expecting dog parent in two months’ time, and I suppose it’s safe to say I’ve gone a bit mad. I’m designing a birth announcement card, and <a href="https://lemonade.waleson.us/" target="_blank">the puppy may or may not already have a website</a>. Help me.</p>

<h3 id="reading">Reading</h3>
<p>I picked up a few great titles at the <a href="https://www.oba.nl/openingstijden/detail.199270.html/oba-oosterdok/" target="_blank">library</a> this month. One that was helpful to get through was, <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/15733923" target="_blank"><em>Loose Cannons Back on Track</em></a>, about managing gifted neurodivergence in the workplace. At the moment, I’m thoroughly enjoying <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/321863.One_Continuous_Mistake" target="_blank"><em>One Continuous Mistake: Four Noble Truths for Writers</em></a> by Gail Sher.</p>

<h3 id="music">Music</h3>
<p>Musically, the year is off to a great start. I’ve made <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-INeMspNSQ0" target="_blank">a new Brian Eno discovery</a> that’s hard not to love, found a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UMJm_97QXHA" target="_blank">Mitski gem</a> that has been on repeat, and added a great track to my work playlist: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_2qsU8FGU_E" target="_blank">Tieduprightnow by Parcels</a>. As always, I’ve compiled a playlist of all of these and more. <a href="https://open.spotify.com/playlist/6Xlr2LlyTQuCdgWd46KNUI?si=980c41a80e134089" target="_blank">Feel free to check it out</a>.</p>

<h3 id="watching">Watching</h3>
<p>I saw <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt7322224/" target="_blank"><em>Triangle of Sadness</em></a> again this month, and loved it more than I did the first time. I appreciate how well this movie understands the finality of our social roles, and how, at the same time, they can be transformed in the blink of an eye. In addition, I am secretly a 13-year-old boy who likes to look at people drowning in their own vomit and excrement.</p>

<p>Anja and I also began watching <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt15677150/" target="_blank"><em>Shrinking</em></a>, which is surprisingly fun. ‘Men’s liberation movement’ like <em>Ted Lasso</em>, but ever so slightly more depressing and realistic.</p>

<h3 id="something-else">Something else</h3>
<p>I find myself looking for great influencers focused on gifted neurodivergence. Like those many awesome YouTubers sharing tips and tricks on how to live with ADHD, but for giftedness, and not in some Mensa kind of way, but just something that’s honest about the challenges one may encounter. Most of what I find is written by pedagogues for parents of gifted children. If you know of anything, feel free to <a href="/hello" target="_blank">let me know</a>.</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/31/that-was-january/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/01/31/that-was-january/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Work</category>
        
          <category>Monthnotes</category>
        
          <category>Music</category>
        
          <category>Cinema</category>
        
          <category>Reading</category>
        
          <category>Neurodivergence</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why doesn't the crosswalk work?</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          
          
          <br />
          <html><body>
<p>There’s a woman who runs a <a href="https://www.athenaeum.nl/winkels/zuidoost" target="_blank">bookshop in De Bijlmer</a>. She has kind eyes that make you want to curl up with a book and a cup of tea. Often when I’m there, she offers just that: tea, and a place to quiet down and dive into an interesting title. She’s running a fine business over there, Cole Verhoeven is.</p>

<p>Aside from bookshop owner she’s also a writer. I love the work she does at <a href="https://www.oneworld.nl/" target="_blank">One World</a>, where she articulates <a href="https://www.oneworld.nl/lezen/opinie/witte-fragiliteit-bestaat-niet/" target="_blank">strong perspectives</a> <a href="https://www.oneworld.nl/lezen/discriminatie/sociaal-onrecht/woke-ooit-een-waarschuwing-voor-racisme-nu-een-conservatief-hondenfluitje/" target="_blank">on antiracism</a> <a href="https://www.oneworld.nl/lezen/opinie/kamala-harris-is-niet-de-eerste-geschikte-zwarte-vrouw/" target="_blank">and equity</a>. A few weeks ago, she sold me this book:</p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_1200/v1674660345/zinzy.website/IMG_9581_iaat6s.jpg" alt=""></p>

<p>When I took it from the shelf, I didn’t know she was the one who wrote it. Eventually, she told me she had drawn inspiration from the questions her child asks her. The questions often leave her bemused, surprised, stunned. I suppose they’re the questions we forget to ask as we grow older.</p>

<p>It’s a perfect coffee table book, deserving of a central place in the house to welcome guests into an atmosphere of curiosity and whimsy.</p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_1200/v1674660350/zinzy.website/FullSizeRender_2_yv2nim.jpg" alt="Page of the book &quot;Why doesn't the crosswalk work?&quot;m with on the left, in Dutch and English, the question &quot;why are all the garbage men brown?&quot;"></p>

<p>One page that stands out to me is this one. There must have been countless times I wondered similar things as a child. Why are the garbage men brown? Why do all the other colored people live on the other side of the tracks? Why don’t I see myself on television?</p>

<p>I imagine the life of Cole’s child, growing up in this part of history, with a Black parent at home to raise him, in one of the most diverse cities in Europe. Access to a Black-owned bookshop that helps people see themselves in others. It makes me feel equal parts envy and calm.</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/23/why-doesnt-the-crosswalk-work/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/01/23/why-doesnt-the-crosswalk-work/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Books</category>
        
          <category>Diversity and inclusion</category>
        
          <category>Amsterdam</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dog park</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          
          
          <br />
          <html><body>
<p>My attempt to lure both Anja and myself outside for some fresh air and a walk was thwarted as soon as I learned the place was out of my favorite bubble tea. We strolled to Flevopark, in my hand an ice cream cone, and on my face the disappointment of a toddler who can’t be satisfied.</p>

<p>The park has a wide field that allows loose dogs to roam freely in the off-season. Even through the trees Anja and I spotted the corgi from half a mile away.</p>

<p>“I mean, we could just go up and chat a little, right? She might have some good tips?” Anja and I wondered, looking for an excuse to get closer to the dog. We must have looked completely adorable, because the face of Kenny’s owner brightened once she noticed us lingering nearby.</p>

<p>She told us about their routine, how he could already stay home alone for most of the day, and how she’d had never heard him bark. Within minutes we learned we all know Lalo, another corgi in the neighborhood.</p>

<p>It’s nice getting to know this new corner of the neighborhood. She and I are dog people now.</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/22/dog-park/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/01/22/dog-park/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Pets</category>
        
          <category>Dogs</category>
        
          <category>Amsterdam</category>
        
          <category>Communities</category>
        
          <category>Anja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>’Love Actually’, once again</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          
          
          <br />
          <html><body>
<p>We had two friends over today. They’re dear to me specifically because we got to know each other intimately during our eating disorder recovery. We promised we’d one day get together and watch <em>Love Actually</em>, much-beloved by each of us.</p>

<p>I’ve developed a habit of watching this film at least once a year. Despite its soft romcomness, homogenous cast, and general lack of depth it has taught me volumes on relationships. I love it more with each viewing.</p>

<p>Today, for the first time, perhaps, I saw its fat-phobia for what it really is. It left a sour taste in my mouth; one that reminds me I’m not the audience of the film, or at least not part of the audience who should feel good after the credits begin to roll.</p>

<p>It’s annoying to see how a home cinema afternoon can make my body experience drop so significantly. I suppose if there’s any month in the year to be confronted with this, it would be International Diet Culture Month, ay?</p>

</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/love-actually-once-again/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/01/21/love-actually-once-again/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Cinema</category>
        
          <category>Reviews</category>
        
          <category>Fatphobia</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Super-recognizer</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          
          
          <br />
          <html><body>
<p>On occasion, Anja will compliment me on my ability to recognize people. I don’t know when I first noticed it myself, but there are actors I recognize even if they played minor characters in an episode of a show I watched 15 years ago. Or I might point out that woman I saw on the bus before COVID hit to a confused Anja.</p>

<p>I’m learning it’s not a very common trait because of the scoffing sound I make whenever Anja confuses Keira Knightly and Daisy Ridley, or Michelle Pfeiffer and Meg Ryan. I only recently became aware how much of a jerk that makes me, and how, if we were in a room full of people, I’d stick out like a sore thumb.</p>

<p>I’ve wondered if I could be classified as a super-recognizer. I remember taking the test a few years ago and stopping halfway through, fearing that I’d see the faces of the people in my dreams and nightmares for all of eternity.</p>

</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/20/super-recognizer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/01/20/super-recognizer/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Memory</category>
        
          <category>Neurodivergence</category>
        
          <category>Anja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prospective dog owners</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          
          
          <br />
          <html><body>
<p>I’m in that supremely annoying stage of prospective dog ownership where I casually interrogate dog owners at parties, curious about their pet’s behavior and the techniques employed, and then silently judge them for their mistakes, exchanging contemptuous glances with Anja in the process.</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/19/prospective-dog-owners/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/01/19/prospective-dog-owners/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Shorts</category>
        
          <category>Dogs</category>
        
          <category>Pets</category>
        
          <category>Anja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The game show</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          
          
          <br />
          <html><body>
<p>This morning I got acquainted with the immigrant anxiety felt by Chinese-American journalist Jiayang Fan about her desire to speak accentless English. In <a href="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/786/its-a-game-show" target="_blank">an episode of one of my favorite podcasts, <em>This American Life</em></a>, Jiayang participated in a game show designed around a talent she claims to possess: the unique ability, inspired by her anxiety, to tell at what age a Chinese-American person came to the United States. The show gave her recordings of three people to prove herself. (She got 0 out of 3.)</p>

<p>Nothing human is alien to me, and neither is Jiayang’s desire to blend in phonetically.</p>

<p>Growing up in the Dutch South, I wasn’t ever unaware of my accent, but it took me enrolling in Utrecht University to become fully aware of the effect it had on others. I could barely make it through class participation without someone chuckling in the back row of lecture hall. I decided that, on the very day I found housing in Utrecht, I would change my accent. These days, few people can tell I’m from the South. I like it that way.</p>

<p>Another thing I’ve always been afraid to sound was “black”. In the Netherlands, that usually means sounding like you were born and (partially) raised in an African country, Suriname, or the Antilles. With no such history, I’m silly to think I could ever fall into that category, which is a fine category in itself. Still, every now and then people will tell me I sound Surinamese. Unable to shake my internalized racism, I always find myself offended when they do.</p>

<p>Today’s episode reminded me of the duality of being a person of color in a conversation about speech. Like Jiayang, I find myself comparing my speech to that of other Black people, forming opinions on what I think is or isn’t “good”. At the same time, I would find it problematic if other, non-Black people were doing it for me. To me, there’s nothing inherently wrong in that distinction; it’s important people can tell their own story and not have it told for them. I’m just struck by the number of times I asked “babe, is this the example we want to give?”</p>

</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/18/the-game-show/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/01/18/the-game-show/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Podcasts</category>
        
          <category>Language</category>
        
          <category>Being black</category>
        
          <category>Being southern</category>
        
          <category>Diversity and inclusion</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>