<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="">
  <channel>
    <title>Zinzy Waleson Geene - RSS</title>
    <description>A researcher, designer, mentor, queer facilitator, and IndieWeb enthusiast from Amsterdam.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4002</link>
    <language></language>
    <copyright>http://localhost:4002/colophon/#copyright</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4002/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>Come back to Chigaco</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<p>Spring is here, I think? I spend the afternoon in the park with ex-colleague-turned-friend Susan, who is celebrating landing a new and challenging job. There’s a boy in the park who’s walking around barefoot. Later we see him on a zipline. I like this scene; it tells me that summer is almost upon us.</p>

<p>I never seem skilled at enjoying whatever season is here. Instead I’m forever yearning for what’s just out of reach. On Javastraat I pass a travel agency, the target audience of which most certainly is concerned with visiting Morocco or Turkey during the summer months. Surprisingly, there’s a wide array of names that would inspire city trips around the world.</p>

<p>Ever since I passed the agency, Andrew Bird’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oecHq2neweA" target="_blank">Pulaski at Night</a> has been in my head non-stop. “Come back to Chigaco, city of, city of light.”</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4002/2023/04/17/come-back-to-chigaco/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4002/2023/04/17/come-back-to-chigaco/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Neighborhood</category>
        
          <category>Funny</category>
        
          <category>Language</category>
        
          <category>Park</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anja's ceramics course</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<p>Today, Lemonade and I visited <a href="https://www.studiopansa.com/studio-pansa-amstel" target="_blank">Studio Pansa Amstel</a>, where Anja has spent the last seven Sundays learning how to work a ceramics wheel. It’s quite the adventure for her, and I love seeing her dive into a new field that’s so different from her day-to-day life and work. Their motto is “dirty hands, clear mind”, and that certainly seems to be the case for Anja.</p>

<p>I saw dozens of gorgeous little cups in the making, each with a unique maker’s mark and the intricate details only found in things that were crafted by hands. I think I’ll sign up for one of Pansa’s courses myself some day.</p>

<div class="breakout">
    <div class="breakout-content">
        <img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/v1681746974/2023-04-16_1_btgjvq.jpg" alt="" class="mb-5">
        <img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/v1681746974/2023-04-16_5_m7uc31.jpg" alt="" class="mb-5">
        <img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/v1681746974/2023-04-16_2_k1jgtv.jpg" alt="" class="mb-5">
    </div>
</div>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4002/2023/04/16/anjas-ceramics-course/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4002/2023/04/16/anjas-ceramics-course/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Anja</category>
        
          <category>Hobbies</category>
        
          <category>Ceramics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meeting Yana and DJ</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<p>What I love most about today’s snapshot is the despair I can see in Lemonade’s eyes even when her entire body is a background blur. DJ is a calm 12-year-old dog, and Lemonade was thrilled to see another dog in our home for the first time, but her energy level was high enough that I eventually brought her back to her crate. It was right in time, too, because the afternoon light filling the living room made for a nice little portrait.</p>

<p>It was wonderful to welcome Yana into our home for the first time. When I hired her in the late Winter of 2022 as our newest UX designer, I knew there was something special about her. Now, well over a year later, I’m pleased to call her a friend. We caught up on career adventures, new trends in the design industry, and of course the joys of being a dog mom.</p>

<p>After Yana and DJ left, Anja and I began winding down for the day. After dinner, we watched the latest episode of the final season of <em>Succession</em>, which may have been my favorite one yet. The characters on this show are so complex and candidly-written. I’m already low-key heartbroken that this show is going to end. At the same time, I’m also pleased to be alive to watch it unfold in real time.</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4002/2023/04/11/meeting-yana-and-dj/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4002/2023/04/11/meeting-yana-and-dj/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Pets</category>
        
          <category>Neighborhood</category>
        
          <category>Friends</category>
        
          <category>Dogs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The cat</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<p>Life sure is different now that we’ve gotten Lemonade on a proper walking schedule. She still feels most comfortable going potty on the puppy pads we have on our balcony, but she absolutely loves going out and exploring the neighborhood.</p>

<p>I’m surprised by how well she walks on a loose leash, and how few issues we’ve had with the stuff she puts in her mouth. I’m hoping to make most use of her imprint period, and that means familiarizing her with as many different things as possible.</p>

<p>I’m happy to find a cat on our morning walk. Lemonade responds to the cat the way I expected a dog would: oozing deference. They stand across from each other for a few minutes, and I reward Lemonade with cheese treats afterwards.</p>

<p>It’s the first step on the road to Lemonade meeting Pookie, my mother-in-law’s cat.</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4002/2023/04/10/the-cat/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4002/2023/04/10/the-cat/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Pets</category>
        
          <category>Neighborhood</category>
        
          <category>Cats</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eight of ten</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<p>When I first set foot in the <a href="https://amsterdam.oudkatholiek.nl/" target="_blank">Old Catholic Church</a> to attend an All Saints service, <a href="/2023/02/12/all-saints-amsterdam/" target="_blank">I knew I had found a special place</a>. Today is the third time I make it to their service, which is always on the second Sunday of the month.</p>

<p>It just so happens that this second Sunday falls on Easter, and it’s perhaps because of this that the service is more crowded than previous times. I see All Saints regulars as well as new people, shy and seemingly hopeful.</p>

<p>One woman in particular stands out to me because she smiles intently at me a few times. She has the demeanor of that good Christian girl from that <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/DunderMifflin/comments/hqskev/scotts_tots_may_be_super_cringe_but_its_nearly/" target="_blank"><em>Office US</em> episode “Christening”</a>.</p>

<p>After service she finds me immediately: “You’re Zinzy from <a href="https://meetup.com/queersalon" target="_blank">Queer Salon</a>, right?” Annika says. Pre-pandemic memories begin to surface, and once she mentions her son I remember her again. “The first time I came here, I thought of you”, she says. We shmooze over crackers and sweet bread, exchange numbers to set a coffee date.</p>

<p>This new church is really a pilot by two reverends hoping to bring fully inclusive Christianity to the Amsterdam expat community. This is service eight out of ten. When I say that out loud, Reverend Howie casually says “yes, we’ll have to talk about that next time.”</p>

<p>I already can’t imagine myself without this community.</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4002/2023/04/09/eight-of-ten/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4002/2023/04/09/eight-of-ten/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Religion</category>
        
          <category>Amsterdam</category>
        
          <category>Queerdom</category>
        
          <category>Queer salon</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A very Mathilde visit</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<p>Much like last year, I’m so excited for Mathilde to visit our house that I get a headache just thinking about it. We’ve known each other 23 years, and, by miracle, our friendship is both acclimatized to our adult lives <em>and</em> as full of energy and curiosity as it was when we met in our first year of secondary school.</p>

<p>She comes bearing gifts: seeds for the garden, dyke poetry, David Sedaris. She knows what I like. We eat, this time around I’ve kept it simple with dishes from the traiteur and not ten separate homemade recipes of intricate delicacies. We talk about what teaching means to her and Anja. We play with Lemonade.</p>

<p>As a friend, Mathilde is very easy to love. Our times together eventually always bring us back to our shared emotional outlet: making music. “I’m nervous to sing around you, Zinzy” she says, but her voice sounds beautiful, warm, and exactly what my piano calls for. When I think of “blue-eyed soul” I think of Mathilde’s voice. We tell each other Anja and I will make it down south this year, and we’ll go for côte de bœuf in Maastricht. I can’t wait.</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4002/2023/04/08/a-very-mathilde-visit/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4002/2023/04/08/a-very-mathilde-visit/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Friends</category>
        
          <category>Pets</category>
        
          <category>Weekends</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Showing up not knowing what will happen</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<p>I met Shervin at the coffee place this morning. We know each other very casually; we used to frequent the same co-working space, we’re LinkedIn friends. He has one of those faces that you just want to meet with a smile.</p>

<p>We exchange how life is treating us, what we’re doing at work. He tells me about his side projects, and how one of them is an invite-only meetup where you attend without knowing what you’ll be doing. He lets me in on secrets around the next meetup, and tells me what kind of activities are involved. It sounds magical.</p>

<p>There’s beauty in the not knowing, we agree. In the whimsy of the unexpected, the sudden connection we may feel with other humans. I tell him his project reminds me of Marina Abramović, whom Anja and I were fortunate enough to meditate with <a href="https://carre.nl/pagina/marina-in-carre" target="_blank">in Carre last year</a>. Participating in <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2010/04/04/nyregion/04about.html" target="_blank">her famous eye-gazing practice</a> with complete strangers was transformative.</p>

<p>I’m glad I got an invitation.</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4002/2023/04/01/showing-up-not-knowing-what-will-happen/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4002/2023/04/01/showing-up-not-knowing-what-will-happen/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Coffee place</category>
        
          <category>Performance art</category>
        
          <category>Meetups</category>
        
          <category>Whimsy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 11: Meeting Patrick</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<ul>
  <li>I got to meet one of my Internet heroes this week: <a href="patrickrhone.com" target="_blank">Patrick Rhone</a> and his family were on a Europe trip, and I was lucky enough <a href="https://www.patrickrhone.net/13189-2/" target="_blank">to catch the planning stage on his blog</a> right in time to extend an invitation. We spent a rainy Monday evening in de Jordaan at <a href="http://www.cafedetuin.nl/" target="_blank">Cafe de Tuin</a>, talking ye olde Internet productivity culture, the arts, politics, hopes and dreams, and how his teenage daughter apparently woke up one night singing “raise a glass to freedom”. Fine people, they are.</li>
  <li>After another week with Lemonade, I’m beginning to feel more confident about raising her to be a well-behaved, confident puppy. For the most part, she’s doing very well. The only real challenge we have is the barking to which she’ll resort every time she’s in the crate but not sleeping. Through trial and error, we’re slowly learning how to help her settle down more easily, and this week, the efforts have begun to pay off.</li>
  <li>I’ve got some exciting news forthcoming that isn’t quite ready for the public just yet, but it has managed to lift my spirits greatly. I’ll be able to write more in the next few weeks, but for now it’s safe to say I’m feeling hopeful, inspired, and ready.</li>
  <li>While Anja had apparently been around to watch season one when it was released, I’ve only now turned onto the wonderful journey that is <em>Abbott Elementary</em>. I would never actually ask the universe for a reboot of <em>The Office: US</em>, but this new mockumentary revolving around a poorly-managed, underfunded Philadelphia public school has exactly the vibe I would’ve hoped to get from that nonexistent reboot. It’s just nice that, with this show, Black people are at the front and center.</li>
  <li>Spring has officially begun, but as one of the regulars at my coffee place said: “the question isn’t when spring begins but when  rain ends”. It seems the weather’s getting better, though, and I can feel I’m on the cusp of storing away my winter coat. It has been a long time coming.</li>
</ul>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4002/2023/03/26/week-11/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4002/2023/03/26/week-11/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Internet friends</category>
        
          <category>Lemonade</category>
        
          <category>Pets</category>
        
          <category>Television</category>
        
          <category>Spring</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A phone call with an old friend</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<p>Happiness today is the ease with which the nun gives me his phone number. Paul is an old friend, or really an old friend of my ex, and we haven’t spoken in eight years.</p>

<p>I had emailed him late last year, missing our kitchen table conversations over coffee and cigarettes. His enormous house, a former school, functioning as his private art studio / gallery. He had replied right away, saying “my phone number is still the same”.</p>

<p>I had lost it long ago, of course.</p>

<p>Today, as I walk home from a coffee run, I think of him, and decide that I should make one last attempt to find his phone number before emailing him again. Looking over his message, I notice he said he no longer lived in the old school, and something about nuns. I suppose I had overlooked it the first time I read it, imagining he lived <em>near</em> a convent rather than in an actual carmelite care facility.</p>

<p>A friendly nun is happy to give me his number right away. A glimpse into a world of old, filled with kind people making generous assumptions. Two minutes later I hear his voice. “hello?”. “I’m not at all surprised you ended up living with a bunch of nuns, Paul” I glee into the phone, remembering our conversations about the Church, his Protestant, mine Catholic. There had always been something about Catholic liturgy that inspired him.</p>

<p>Despite his heavy bout of Covid, double pneumonia, and delirium, he still remembers me. Within minutes, we slide back into a conversation that never really began and never really ended.</p>

<p>Both of us are still the same to one another.</p>

<p>He gives me splinters of stories: a thieving cleaning lady, the storage and eventual donation of his body of work, the conversations he has with his neighbor priest. I tell him about Anja, about our small apartment, and about my eternal journey finding a Christian place I can call home.</p>

<p>We agree that I’ll come visit soon, and I will. A few misremembered numbers and names aside, he’s still the same old Paul. But by God, he nearly wasn’t here, and I don’t have time to waste.</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4002/2023/03/16/a-phone-call-with-an-old-friend/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4002/2023/03/16/a-phone-call-with-an-old-friend/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Friends</category>
        
          <category>Phone calls</category>
        
          <category>Happiness</category>
        
          <category>Catholicism</category>
        
          <category>Christianity</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 10: Outings</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<ul>
  <li>It snowed a few times this week and I was as baffled as I always am to see it happening in March. I don’t have a great understanding of what the weather’s supposed to do in a given period of the year.</li>
  <li>After two weeks of cocooning, we’ve finally been taking Lemonade out to various places. I aim to take her out at least once a day, usually to the park or a walk around the block. We also visited my favorite coffee place twice. It’s wonderful to see she’s such a relaxed and curious dog.</li>
  <li>This was my last full week off. I still have a few days left and then I head back into work. I don’t know how people work after they first got a puppy, and I’m grateful I was able to take this time off.</li>
  <li>I attended service at All Saints again. It was an intimate gathering with a rather inspiring reflection comparing “giving up” to “letting go” for Lent. I feel like I never get Lent right: I drop in too late, don’t see it all the way through, and this always makes me feel like I’m not a proper Christian. Regardless, it’s great to become acquainted with All Saints. Its focus on inclusivity gives me goosebumps.</li>
  <li>Lemonade met the other corgi in the building, Lalo. At only ten weeks older than she is, he towered over her as they played, but she didn’t let that bother her. He was so sweet playing with her, using his strength in a very gentle way. Here’s to hoping they’ll become best friends.</li>
  <li>
<a href="https://anneliewambeek.com" target="_blank">Annelie</a> came over for tea and lemon punitions. She had been gone for a few weeks and I had missed her. She’s Lemonade’s godmother, and as they met in real life for the first time it was clear to see why this is so.</li>
  <li>Anja started her ceramics course at Studio Pansa. On Sunday she had her second class, and she took pictures. She’s such a fast learner, and the pots she made came out beautifully. I’m proud of her.</li>
</ul>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4002/2023/03/12/week-10/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4002/2023/03/12/week-10/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Television</category>
        
          <category>Lemonade</category>
        
          <category>Dogs</category>
        
          <category>Pets</category>
        
          <category>Anja</category>
        
          <category>Annelie</category>
        
          <category>Church</category>
        
          <category>Ceramics</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>