<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="">
  <channel>
    <title>Zinzy Waleson Geene - RSS</title>
    <description>Zinzy Waleson Geene is a researcher, designer, facilitator, and IndieWeb enthusiast from Amsterdam.</description>
    <link>https://www.zinzy.website</link>
    <language></language>
    <copyright>https://www.zinzy.website/colophon/#copyright</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://www.zinzy.website/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>Now: November 2022</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          An overview of what I'm up to these days
          
          <br />
          <ul>
  <li>In Amsterdam simultaneously enjoying and dreading the cold</li>
  <li>At <a class="internal-link" href="/leeruniek">Leeruniek</a> thoroughly enjoying transitioning from product management back to design management.</li>
  <li>Thinking of getting a corgi puppy</li>
  <li>Working tirelessly to recover from an <a class="internal-link" href="/eating-disorder">eating disorder</a></li>
  <li>Invested in my <a class="internal-link" href="/yoga">yoga</a> and <a class="internal-link" href="/meditation">meditation</a> practice</li>
  <li>Getting ready to buy a stage piano</li>
</ul>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=Now:%20November%202022">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.zinzy.website/2022/12/13/now</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.zinzy.website/2022/12/13/now</guid>
        
          
          <category>Now</category>
          
        
        
          <category>Now</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I hate, fear, and suck at</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          A year ago, as part of my recovery journey, my therapist asked me: 'What are your core values? Like, what are your deepest needs and desires?' She reminded me last week that, instead of pausing to think of a response, I laughed straight in her face.
          
          <br />
          <p>A year ago, as part of my <a class="internal-link" href="/eating-disorder">recovery journey</a>, my therapist asked me:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>What are your core values? Like, what are your deepest needs and desires?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>She reminded me last week that, instead of pausing to think of a response, I laughed straight in her face.</p>

<p>Historically, I’ve had trouble identifying what I want, need, desire, hope for, and dream of.</p>

<p>In-patient treatment has helped train that muscle, though. My first vision board there consisted of kind interactions with strangers in coffee houses, while other clients were planning to pursue a Master’s or travel the world. On the flight back I made my first-ever attempt at a <a class="internal-link" href="/bucket-list">Bucket list</a>.</p>

<p>Treatment taught me a hack that’s now helping me figure out what I hope 2023 will look like. Instead of identifying what I <em>do</em> hope, want, and yearn for, I look at what I <em>don’t</em>. What I hate can tell me something about what I fear. What I fear can, in turn, lead me to what I desire. Knowing what I suck at can help me identify challenges I might encounter as I move towards those desires.</p>

<p>As the year comes to a close, and as I figure out once again, but now from scratch, <a class="internal-link" href="/how-i-life-os">How I Life OS</a>, I’m asking myself:</p>

<ul>
  <li>What do I hate?</li>
  <li>What do I fear?</li>
  <li>What do I suck at?</li>
</ul>

<p>Rather than seeing my weak points as things I must improve in order to be healthy and happy, I try to figure out how I can use these characteristics to my benefit. I’m looking forward to optimizing <em>for</em> them, so I can have a realistic outlook as I learn and thrive.</p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=What%20I%20hate,%20fear,%20and%20suck%20at">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.zinzy.website/2022/12/07/what-i-hate-fear-and-suck-at</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.zinzy.website/2022/12/07/what-i-hate-fear-and-suck-at</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Reflection</category>
        
          <category>Life changes</category>
        
          <category>Recovery</category>
        
          <category>Self care</category>
        
          <category>Practices</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 48: Chinese food</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          The week was fairly quiet: I'm still having trouble getting enough rest, which leads to headaches and dizzy spells, but with enough breaks, naps, and beauty sleep I seem to be on a path to feeling better.
          
          <br />
          <ul>
  <li>The week was fairly quiet: I’m still having trouble getting enough rest, which leads to headaches and dizzy spells, but with enough breaks, naps, and beauty sleep I seem to be on a path to feeling better.</li>
  <li>I’m continuing to settle back into work, and I love working on my own design assignment. I can see how much I missed the tangible, practical design work, as well as design collaboration.</li>
  <li>Don’t tell A, but I indulged in a new Filofax setup for 2023. I got my hands on both their <a href="https://uk.filofax.com/collections/a5-refills-for-organisers-and-clipbook/products/minimal-week-to-view-diary-a5-2023">Week on Two Pages Diary</a>, and their <a href="https://uk.filofax.com/products/one-day-on-a-page-diary-with-appointments-a5-2023?_pos=1&amp;_sid=315704f6e&amp;_ss=r">One Day on a Page Diary</a>, to give myself ample space to organize. I’m quite exicted to try the week pages, which have a monthly planner section as well.</li>
  <li>I watched <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Franklin_Delano_Floyd#Death_of_Suzanne_Sevakis">Girl In The Picture</a>, and all I can say is: I have quite the stomach for gruesome stories, but this shook me.</li>
  <li>I also watched <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt11188206/">15 Minutes of Shame</a> and I loved it, particularly the connection they made to medieval punishment. It made me think back to my time as a student, getting acquainted with medieval literature for the first time.</li>
  <li>I had the 👏🏽  best 👏🏽  Chinese 👏🏽  food of my life, at <a href="https://www.hoitin.nl/">Hoi Tin</a>.</li>
</ul>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=Week%2048:%20Chinese%20food">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.zinzy.website/2022/12/03/week-48</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.zinzy.website/2022/12/03/week-48</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 47: Booster</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          A bit of a dreary week, but at least we have great television.
          
          <br />
          <ul>
  <li>I forgot how the COVID booster can make you feel as though, temporarily, the world may well be ending. I got it earlier this week, and it left me with a sore arm and that dreadful, ridiculous sensation that accompanies a flu that lasts a week too long. I mimic my late stepfather, who used to wimper like a puppy whenever he got a cold.</li>
  <li>I still do well to limit my hours of screen time. Before I know it, I’m stuck with a headache and dizzy spell.</li>
  <li>Spotify’s Discover Weekly was on point this week. Aside from lovely “beards and log cabin” tunes, as I call 70s soft rock, I’ve fallen hard for the hyper pop track <a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/4n0sVfRnd0UJsqcbPj7GqN?si=Z5yeyS2xTjOEWlOSI5EnmQ">“Notice”</a> by Moe Shop and Toriena.</li>
  <li>We raced through another season of <em>The Crown</em>, this time with the excellent Elizabeth Debicki as Diana. I love how she manages to capture Diana so well despite <em>and</em> because of her camp-adjacent interpretation of her. I wonder if she ever got a sore neck during taping.</li>
  <li>After protesting for weeks, I’ve finally let A turn on the heating. So far, I haven’t had much up-close experience with the energy crisis the world is currently facing, and I don’t want that to change. It’s great to feel my toes, though.</li>
</ul>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=Week%2047:%20Booster">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.zinzy.website/2022/11/27/week-47</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.zinzy.website/2022/11/27/week-47</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Vaccination</category>
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Notes on my web mastery</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          <p>Recently, I’ve been making some great progress with my personal website. While I normally don’t engage in technical ballets on the goings-on of this website, I feel it’s relevant to document what I’ve learnt and done, if only for posterity.</p>

          
          <br />
          <p>Recently, I’ve been making some great progress with my personal website. While I normally don’t engage in technical ballets on the goings-on of this website, I feel it’s relevant to document what I’ve learnt and done, if only for posterity.</p>

<h3 id="tools">Tools</h3>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a>: as is often the case for me, this site is built using my favorite flat-file content management system</li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/">Github</a>: hosts the code for this website</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.netlify.com/">Netlify</a>: serves the content to my website</li>
  <li><a href="https://obsidian.md/">Obsidian</a>: I write in a single Obsidian vault</li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/denolehov/obsidian-git">obsidian-git</a>: helps me manage  the version control of my Obsidian content</li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/marketplace/actions/push-git-subdirectory-as-branch">Push git subdirectory as branch</a>: a Github action that lets me publish a part of the content of my Obsidian vault to a separate repository</li>
  <li><a href="https://mtsknn.fi/blog/netlify-updating-private-git-submodule/">Git submodule</a>: my separate repository is pulled into my website’s code base</li>
  <li><a href="https://mtsknn.fi/blog/how-to-trigger-daily-netlify-builds-using-github-actions/">Netlify build hook</a>: every day, Netlify looks for new content and publishes it to my website</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="why-this-is-great">Why this is great</h3>
<ul>
  <li>I hold the strong belief that <a class="internal-link" href="/tools-don-t-matter">* Tools don’t matter</a>. This means, among other things, that I don’t like to be limited to using particular platforms or apps to write. I want to see my files in a folder that I can move around. Jekyll allows me to do just this.</li>
  <li>My website is a text-heavy space: most of what you’ll find on here is written content. As a knowledge worker, writing is an integral part of my daily life. Many of the things I write are not for public consumption, but they are closely linked to things that <em>are</em>. To avoid duplicate content and awkward linking, it was important for me to manage my text files in a single space, one Obsidian vault.</li>
  <li>I have a tendency to tinker a lot on my website. This can make it so that I spend more time trying out new things and changing the design than I do writing. Having my code base and content separated helps me focus more on writing things that are meaningful to me.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="some-things-i-havent-figured-out-yet">Some things I haven’t figured out yet</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Is it worthwhile for me to publish more granular IndieWeb post types such as notes and likes? Do I care about them? Am I making them only to show them? What’s their value if I cannot automate this process? Does the technical implementation change if I push said content to a git repository that consists of only notes?</li>
  <li>What does a proper dark mode look like?</li>
  <li>Do I want to continue my barebones experiment and document the <a class="internal-link" href="/discomfort-of-vanity">Discomfort of vanity</a>? Or am I ready for something more modern?</li>
  <li>How in the world do I even go about Micropub and Webmentions?</li>
</ul>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=Notes%20on%20my%20web%20mastery">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.zinzy.website/2022/11/26/notes-on-my-web-mastery</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.zinzy.website/2022/11/26/notes-on-my-web-mastery</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Indieweb</category>
        
          <category>Web development</category>
        
          <category>Tinkering</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rest</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          Simmering down is a challenge this week. I wake, daily before 6am, and jump straight into the day.
          
          <br />
          <p>Simmering down is a challenge this week. I wake, daily before 6am, and jump straight into the day. My jump doesn’t land me in a FOMO-inducing Instagram feed or a busy news site, but on a blank screen that waits eagerly as I type my 1,000 words of the morning. It’s another one of the <a class="internal-link" href="/habits">Habits</a> I picked up this autumn. Me, the darkness outside, and a soft light in the living room acquainting me with the day. It’s pleasing to meet myself, unfiltered.</p>

<p>It’s also one of the few moments of solitude and focus I allow myself this week, apparently. Now that I’m beginning to reintegrate back into work at <span title="There is no note that matches this link." class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets">[[</span>  Public/_notes/Leeruniek  <span class="invalid-link-brackets">]]</span></span>, I seem to have forgotten how much down time my body still requires. I’ve received a work assignment, on which I’ll get to work independently, and I’m excited. Curious. Hungry. On the cusp of small-scale overdrive. I had to stop working precisely because of this.</p>

<p>It’s boring.</p>

<p>Then I remember and old way to find calm and relaxation. <a href="https://www.iheart.com/podcast/105-stuff-you-should-know-26940277/">The voices of Josh Clark and Chuck Bryant, telling me about stuff I should know</a>.</p>

<h3 id="whats-top-of-mind-right-now">What’s top of mind right now</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Saw Hannah Gadsby’s <a class="internal-link" href="/body-of-work">Body of Work</a> and had a brief, cogent crush on her</li>
  <li>Saw a large number of Twitter folks join the much kinder Mastodon club. I’m slowly beginning to feel comfortable about the platform, and how it invites me to share my thoughts.</li>
  <li>I’m thinking a lot about what ex-Twitter designer <a href="https://tech.lgbt/@jon@social.lot23.com/109372263710282940">Jon Bell</a> said about Twitter’s user experience trajectory. I keep saying out loud how central the difference between <a class="internal-link" href="/do-the-right-thing">doing the right thing</a> and <a class="internal-link" href="/do-the-thing-right">doing the thing right</a> is to the design work I do.</li>
</ul>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=Rest">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.zinzy.website/2022/11/20/rest</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.zinzy.website/2022/11/20/rest</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes for week 44, 2022</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          <p>The weather has officially reached a temperature that requires me to buy a new coat. I dread it. Unlike most other types of clothing, coats and jackets never seem to suit me, regardless of the style. To soften the blow of having to order several coats on the Internet hoping one will work for me, I granted myself three sets of retro socks.</p>

          
          <br />
          <p>The weather has officially reached a temperature that requires me to buy a new coat. I dread it. Unlike most other types of clothing, coats and jackets never seem to suit me, regardless of the style. To soften the blow of having to order several coats on the Internet hoping one will work for me, I granted myself three sets of retro socks.</p>

<p>I finished reading <a class="internal-link" href="/the-midnight-library">The Midnight Library</a>, which I had borrowed from <a href="https://www.anneliewambeek.com/">Annelie</a>. It sure has been a long time since I last read a book that was both so entertaining and easygoing. It feels borderline young adult, and entirely unpretentious.</p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=Weeknotes%20for%20week%2044,%202022">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.zinzy.website/2022/11/06/week-44</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.zinzy.website/2022/11/06/week-44</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Reading</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Now: October 2022</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          
          
          <br />
          <ul>
  <li>
    <p>I’m interested to read some of Germaine Greer’s work. I like how, beyond the initial shock value of things she has said, there is a very blatant truth that I’m happy to engage with.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>After six weeks in the Algarve to continue recovering from an <a class="internal-link" href="/eating-disorder">Eating disorder</a>, I’m readjusting to bustling Amsterdam and establishing new <a class="internal-link" href="/habits">Habits</a>.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Before Portugal, I was notoriously rubbish at dreaming about what I’d want my life to be like. I’ve returned with a renewed sense of agency, and a small-but-growing <a class="internal-link" href="/bucket-list">bucket list</a> to boot.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Getting settled it at my new <a class="internal-link" href="/yoga">yoga</a> studio Thrive Yoga.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Learning <a class="internal-link" href="/yiddish">Yiddish</a> in the early hours.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=Now:%20October%202022">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.zinzy.website/2022/10/24/now</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.zinzy.website/2022/10/24/now</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Now</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Now: May 2022</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          
          
          <br />
          <p>Thinking about visual literacy, in part because the bulk of <a href="https://anjawaleson.notion.site/Anja-Waleson-0182c8df804b4b12ab6e70b5b5795a55">Anja</a>’s academic work is focused on it right now, but also because I just love telling people off whenever they say that <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2020/dec/07/a-novel-idea-is-the-book-always-better-than-the-film">“the book is better than the movie”</a>.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>I’m interested in learning about buddhism, but I don’t know where to start. Everything seems either too technical or too Pinterst quotesque. A trusted source tells me Pema Chödrön, Thich Nhat Hanh, and Herman Hesse’s <em>Siddharta</em> are good entry point. Off we go.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I’ve been mentoring over on <a href="https://adplist.org/mentors/zinzy-nev-geene">ADPList</a> for a while now, and I can only say I’m truly enjoying it. It’s great to work with researchers, designers, and product managers in different stages of their careers.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>After months of being, in essense, a recruitment manager, we added two new amazing talents to our team. I have one more role to fill, but I’m very pleased that the bulk of my time at work now goes to research, **strategy, mentoring, and operations. Feels good to be back. In all of it, I’m working to rely on my intuition, and to ask better questions.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I’ve been experimenting with new dishes: Teriyaki steak rolls, and Miso Yaki Onigiri</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>We’ve been into <em>The Staircase</em>. I remember watching it years ago, and now that the rather satisfying HBO series is available, we’re rewatching the documentary for extra context. It’s striking to see what role anti-queer rhetoric played in the investigation and media coverage.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Things look a little bit different on this site, and that’s mainly because I built it again, this time using Maxime Vaillancourt’s <a href="https://github.com/maximevaillancourt/digital-garden-jekyll-template">digital garden Jekyll template</a>.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Attended <a class="internal-link" href="/uxinsight-festival-2022">UXInsight Festival 2022</a> and enjoyed it.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=Now:%20May%202022">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.zinzy.website/2022/05/28/now</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.zinzy.website/2022/05/28/now</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Now</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weeknotes for week 16, 2022</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          <p>Each year I’m less embarrassed to say it: I don’t like that stretch of time during the Dutch Springtime when no work week is normal. Aside from the usual Christian holidays there’s King’s Day and Liberation Day, and I’ve found it really messes with my head. I don’t mind them much looking ahead (like I did last week, but having to live through it could well be too much for me.</p>

          
          <br />
          <p>Each year I’m less embarrassed to say it: I don’t like that stretch of time during the Dutch Springtime when no work week is normal. Aside from the usual Christian holidays there’s King’s Day and Liberation Day, and I’ve found it really messes with my head. I don’t mind them much looking ahead (like I did last week, but having to live through it could well be too much for me.</p>

<p>This week, I learn that bolognese is a great base for chili, as long as you add enough cumin, beef, and beer. We watch <em>The Undoing</em>, which is a surprisingly great decision of Hugh Grant.</p>


          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=Weeknotes%20for%20week%2016,%202022">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.zinzy.website/2022/04/23/week-16</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.zinzy.website/2022/04/23/week-16</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Television</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>