<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="">
  <channel>
    <title>Zinzy Waleson Geene - RSS</title>
    <description>This is a quiet street on the Internet, a place for soft stances, lived experiences, and critical notes on the things I hold dear.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <language></language>
    <copyright>http://localhost:4000/colophon/#copyright</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <ul>
  <li>Updated the general UI of this website by adding a softer background color</li>
  <li>Added a <a href="https://github.com/zinzy/zinzy.website/blob/6b0d3cf68e30b2c6d38e81dc3b3d7f4517d44913/_layouts/index.html">splice method I used earlier</a> to <a href="https://indieweb.org/photo">photo posts</a>, which allows me to alter the size of the images served through Cloudinary</li>
  <li>Merged <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_notes</code> contents into my <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_posts</code> folder so that my dated content is organized in a single place (this is convenient for pagination purposes)</li>
  <li>Styled the <a href="/tags">tags page</a></li>
  <li>Updated layout of an individual tag page so that short notes and posts are grouped accordingly</li>
</ul>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 10:53:02 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/12/31/07-53-02</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/12/31/07-53-02</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Changelog</category>
        
          <category>Website</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p>Peel off party</p>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 07:54:03 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/12/22/08-53-gmt-1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/12/22/08-53-gmt-1</guid>
        
          
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Annual review at 36</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p>In one way or another, the number 36 has felt like a milestone birthday for a long time. As a tween, I imagined the glamorous autonomy that came with being 36 because I was hooked on watching the televised adventures of a foursome of privileged White women in Manhattan. Now, finally at 36, it feels important that I could’ve had a child as an adult who would now also be an adult. I say “adult” but we all remember the self-important idiots we were at 18.</p>

<p>I enjoyed reading <a href="https://www.designswarm.com/blog/2023/12/end-of-year-review-5/">Deschamps-Sonsino</a>’ annual review, so here’s mine.</p>

<h3 id="1-what-did-you-do-in-2023-that-youd-never-done-before">1. What did you do in 2023 that you’d never done before?</h3>
<p>Find belonging in a <a href="http://allsaintsamsterdam.church/">Christian community</a></p>

<h3 id="2-did-you-keep-your-new-years-resolutions-and-will-you-make-more-for-next-year">2. Did you keep your New Years’ resolutions, and will you make more for next year?</h3>
<p>I didn’t make any</p>

<h3 id="3-did-anyone-close-to-you-give-birth">3. Did anyone close to you give birth?</h3>
<p>No</p>

<h3 id="4-did-anyone-close-to-you-die">4. Did anyone close to you die?</h3>
<p>AA’s father passed</p>

<h3 id="5-what-countries-did-you-visit">5. What countries did you visit?</h3>
<p><a href="/2023/08/17/norway-et-al">Germany, Denmark, Sweden, and Norway by Tesla in the Summertime</a></p>

<h3 id="6-what-would-you-like-to-have-in-2024-that-you-lacked-in-2023">6. What would you like to have in 2024 that you lacked in 2023?</h3>
<p>Headspace to see <em>what is</em></p>

<h3 id="7-what-date-from-2023-will-remain-etched-upon-your-memory">7. What date from 2023 will remain etched upon your memory?</h3>
<p>February 25</p>

<h3 id="8-what-was-your-biggest-achievement-of-the-year">8. What was your biggest achievement of the year?</h3>
<p>Landing a job in my dream field: enterprise healthcare SaaS</p>

<h3 id="9-what-was-your-biggest-failure">9. What was your biggest failure?</h3>
<p>Not walking enough</p>

<h3 id="10-did-you-suffer-illness-or-injury">10. Did you suffer illness or injury?</h3>
<p>Covid in early Winter</p>

<h3 id="11-what-was-the-best-thing-you-bought">11. What was the best thing you bought?</h3>
<p>A Polaroid camera</p>

<h3 id="12-whose-behaviour-merited-celebration">12. Whose behaviour merited celebration?</h3>
<p>Sierra for opening Bar Bario, which I discovered this year</p>

<h3 id="13-whose-behaviour-made-you-appalled-and-depressed">13. Whose behaviour made you appalled and depressed?</h3>
<p>Non-Jewish Americans hurling zionazism at Israeli pro-Palestinian protesters. I fear this war will be the end of us, but intellectually</p>

<h3 id="14-where-did-most-of-your-money-go">14. Where did most of your money go?</h3>
<p>To a YNAB category I call “🍱 Foreign Kitchens”</p>

<h3 id="15-what-did-you-get-really-really-really-excited-about">15. What did you get really, really, really excited about?</h3>
<p>Godzilla</p>

<h3 id="16-what-songalbum-will-always-remind-you-of-2023">16. What song/album will always remind you of 2023?</h3>
<p>Mitski’s “Francis Forever”</p>

<h3 id="17-compared-to-this-time-last-year-you-are">17. Compared to this time last year, you are:</h3>
<p>Better able to embrace all aspects of myself</p>

<h3 id="18-what-do-you-wish-youd-done-more-of">18. What do you wish you’d done more of?</h3>
<p>Walk</p>

<h3 id="19-what-do-you-wish-youd-done-less-of">19. What do you wish you’d done less of?</h3>
<p>Reddit</p>

<h3 id="20-how-will-you-be-spending-the-winter-holidays">20. How will you be spending the Winter holidays?</h3>
<p>Enjoying the lack of commitments. Christmas Eve is a Jewish NYC tradition: best Chinese in town</p>

<h3 id="21-who-did-you-spend-the-most-time-on-the-phone-with">21. Who did you spend the most time on the phone with?</h3>
<p>Mary Elizabeth</p>

<h3 id="22-did-you-fall-in-love-in-2023">22. Did you fall in love in 2023?</h3>
<p>Yes, with a dog</p>

<h3 id="23-what-was-your-favorite-tv-program">23. What was your favorite TV program?</h3>
<p>Literally can’t even remember — tells me something about how much time I spend watching forgettable things</p>

<h3 id="24-do-you-hate-anyone-now-that-you-didnt-hate-this-time-last-year">24. Do you hate anyone now that you didn’t hate this time last year?</h3>
<p>No</p>

<h3 id="25-what-was-the-best-books-you-read">25. What was the best book(s) you read?</h3>
<p>Naomi Klein’s <em>Doppelgänger</em> - also the only one I actually finished</p>

<h3 id="26-what-was-your-greatest-musical-discovery">26. What was your greatest musical discovery?</h3>
<p>Marc Rebillet’s “Late to Work”, also the LoFi Pokémon playlist</p>

<h3 id="27-what-did-you-want-and-get">27. What did you want and get?</h3>
<p>A great new job</p>

<h3 id="28-what-did-you-want-and-not-get">28. What did you want and not get?</h3>
<p>A cute outfit for the dog</p>

<h3 id="29-what-were-your-favorite-films-of-this-year">29. What were your favorite films of this year?</h3>
<p><em>Godzilla Minus One</em>, <em>Talk To Me</em>, and <em>Past Lives</em></p>

<h3 id="30-what-did-you-do-on-your-birthday-and-how-old-were-you">30. What did you do on your birthday, and how old were you?</h3>
<p>On my 36th birthday, I spent a guilt-free day going to the library, out for lunch, to Bar Bario, and to 101 Gowrie</p>

<h3 id="31-what-one-thing-would-have-made-your-year-immeasurably-more-satisfying">31. What one thing would have made your year immeasurably more satisfying?</h3>
<p>More alone time</p>

<h3 id="32-how-would-you-describe-your-personal-fashion-concept-in-2023">32. How would you describe your personal fashion concept in 2023?</h3>
<p>Office lesbian / mountain lesbian</p>

<h3 id="33-what-kept-you-sane">33. What kept you sane?</h3>
<p>Making music</p>

<h3 id="34-which-celebritypublic-figure-did-you-fancy-the-most">34. Which celebrity/public figure did you fancy the most?</h3>
<p>Philip Seymour Hoffman, as per usual</p>

<h3 id="35-what-political-issue-stirred-you-the-most">35. What political issue stirred you the most?</h3>
<p>Dutch white people being so shocked at the election results</p>

<h3 id="36-who-did-you-miss">36. Who did you miss?</h3>
<p>Mathilde</p>

<h3 id="37-who-was-the-best-new-person-you-met">37. Who was the best new person you met?</h3>
<p>Mehdi</p>

<h3 id="38-tell-us-a-valuable-life-lesson-you-learned-in-2023">38. Tell us a valuable life lesson you learned in 2023.</h3>
<p>Get out of your own way</p>

<h3 id="39-quote-a-song-lyric-that-sums-up-your-year">39. Quote a song lyric that sums up your year?</h3>
<p>(I’ll have to think about it)</p>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/12/21/annual-review-at-36</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/12/21/annual-review-at-36</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Annual review</category>
        
          <category>Lists</category>
        
          <category>Questions</category>
        
          <category>Community</category>
        
          <category>Birthday</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A lifetime without representation</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p>My friend and I reunite after 18 months. I missed him dearly, but once we sit down for ramen we can both tell it’s like we were there yesterday. I talk about him often. He’s the person who was so discombobulated by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/26029077">Dutch white innocence</a>, that he felt more comfortable going back to the Middle East to live in the closet. He’s doing better now. No more crack, and the spinning class is surprisingly inclusive. He even joined a theatre group.</p>

<p>“Remember when you scolded me because my website was in Times New Roman?” I ask him. He doesn’t. Back when this happened, he was working a Dutch corporate job. Part of him, or perhaps all of him, must have been so embarrassed to learn he’d sent his UX-hopeful coworker to a webpage that looked like it never left the late nineties.</p>

<p>“Oh look, another book on personal branding” I say as we walk into American Book Center. “That’s actually really what I need” he says. It’s because he’s hoping to be invited to SoHo House Amsterdam. “That reminds me of, what’s her name… Anna Delvey?” I say. That’s exactly what it is, he tells me. It’s a private place for selected Amsterdam creatives. A country club in the city.</p>

<p>“It’s great. You can’t take pictures in there, they let you connect with other creatives, and it’s 200 euros a month. My friend rebranded herself in such a brilliant way, check out this picture of her with her paintings on Instagram. She got an invite right away.” When I note that he moved a five-hour plane ride away from SoHo House Spuistraat, he seems surprised.</p>

<p>At Coffee Company, he shows me his blog, but he holds his hand over the title, of which I manage to catch a glimpse. It’s such a weird name I forget it instantly, but the writing is beautiful. I’m saddened by Gen Z’s inability to just use their own bleeding name for stuff. I don’t think the fragmentation is doing them any good.</p>

<p>I peer pressure him into getting one of those silly hand treatments at Lush, where the people always seem a little too eager to greet you. The person giving the treatment has a pronoun button on their apron, but still I get it wrong. “Zinzy, her pronouns are they/them” my friend says. Minutes later, I joke how I need an applause for managing to use the correct pronoun. The two most oppressed people on Kalverstraat, and we’re mere inches away from becoming the boomers we avoid.</p>

<p>We finally land at Bar Bario, where the Callaloo Hoek staff has come down with covid. What a waste of a good appetite, I think, as I Uber us Ranchi sandwiches. Like two people on a date that can’t find its pace, we take turns asking each other questions from the jar on the table. “When was the first time you felt represented by the media?” I ask him. “Never”.</p>

<p>“<em>This</em> is your SoHo House,” I say, waving my arms feverishly at the Black pride on the walls and queer people of color at the bar. “<em>Your</em> people are <em>here</em>”. He cries a little bit, but because he can’t escape the characteristics of his generation, I can’t tell if he’s faking it, method acting, or just unable to cry like a normal person.</p>

]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/12/20/a-lifetime-without-representation</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/12/20/a-lifetime-without-representation</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Website</category>
        
          <category>Indieweb</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p>Knowing I’m at home in Amsterdam is getting on the tram, seeing the same conductor as a few hours ago, spotting various people whose faces I know. A city as a village, but in a non-insular way.</p>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 21:25:37 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/12/17/20-23-gmt-1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/12/17/20-23-gmt-1</guid>
        
          
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p>The split personality trend was… a moment!</p>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 05:26:42 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/11/30/06-26-gmt-1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/11/30/06-26-gmt-1</guid>
        
          
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 47: Geert Milders</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <h3 id="covid">Covid</h3>
<p>It’s curious to see my response to a bout of Covid is not much different from what it was in early 2020. Despite a <a href="/2023/11/19/week-46">negative test</a>, symptoms tell me everything I need to know. I have to remind myself every day this week that, given the regulations, I’m not obliged to quarantine. Nevertheless, Anja and I are both barely able to walk the dog. I work half days, and spend my afternoons in bed with hot water bottles.</p>

<p>Later in the week, I have cabin fever that is so intense it makes me cry in the park a little bit. On Sunday, the only thing I’m left with is a stuffy nose as well as some fatigue. God, I hope I don’t develop long Covid.</p>

<h3 id="consuming">Consuming</h3>
<p>Anja and I watch season two of <em>Somebody Somewhere</em>. It makes me regain a new appreciation for Bridget Everett’s physical comedy, new sincerity, and sass. I wish she and I were friends.</p>

<h3 id="tinkering">Tinkering</h3>
<p>I make some changes to my website this week, centering a page of text with links on the homepage. Sometimes, I feel bad that I don’t take screenshots every time I change it. But I suppose my continuous redesign strategy prevents that from being realistic.</p>

<h3 id="politics">Politics</h3>
<p>On Wednesday, the country has her very own 2016 American election result: after 20 years of being (rightfully) ridiculed as a far right party, PVV is finally the biggest, taking 37 of 150 seats in the House. Most people in my safe, progressive, friendly Amsterdam that I’ve spoken with are gobsmacked. Party leader Geert Wilders has become Geert Milders. A part of me is angry and sad, but a much larger part says: welcome to my world.</p>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 09:16:15 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/11/25/week-47</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/11/25/week-47</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 46: Osama</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <ul>
  <li>I’m making an attempt this week to make my weeknotes more of a personal record rather than a performance of how exciting my week is. What I’ve written answers the question I might ask myself seven years from now: what was life like this week?</li>
  <li>I went on the road for on-site research on Tuesday, and was delighted by the particular nursing home that we visited. It seems many Dutch healthcare organizations have understood that environments that resemble the real-life environments of patients contribute to their overall wellbeing. The various spaces we saw were tailored to what life must have been like when the elderly clients were younger: a fifties barber shop, a diner-like restaurant. It was endearing. More professionally, I continue to be stunned by the working lives of people in healthcare. Having to balance tight budgets and strict schedules on the one hand and genuinely wanting the best for clients on the other is not an easy feat.</li>
  <li>It seems like I did pick up Covid while there.</li>
  <li>I’ve begun watching <em>Monarch: Legacy of Monsters</em> and I love my life. The farther I become removed from the humanities major version of myself, the easier it becomes to admit I love monster disaster stories.</li>
  <li>I’ve also begun watching the second season of <em>The Morning Show</em>, and two episodes in I understand why Anja urged me to really, <em>really</em> give it a try. Reese Witherspoon making out with Julianna Margulies is not the stuff of dreams I thought I needed, but here we are. Acting, storyline etc. also good.</li>
  <li>The Israel-Hamas War continues to rage, which has begun to feel like a weird name for the conflict. I wonder what it means that, when I Google those words, the Wikipedia entry to which I’m directed is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2023_Hamas_attack_on_Israel">
2023 Hamas attack on Israel</a>.</li>
  <li>I will never have first-hand experience of what it means to be a Jewish person in the world today, although I’ve been having a second-hand experience that has been leaving me… perturbed. When people discover my partner is Jewish, the tone of the conversation shifts. Not in a pro-Palestinian way, but in the way Jenna Maroney felt the urge to touch Liz Lemon’s hand after learning that Liz had met Oprah on a flight (which, of course, turned out to be a random Black woman).</li>
  <li>While I tested negative, I did spend Friday evening and night in bed with a fever and a body that felt as though it had been hit by a truck. Anja did test positive on Sunday, and so now we’re quarantining. March 2020 all over again.</li>
  <li>I keep thinking a lot about Osama Bin Laden. About the lack of context given by the journalist who shared parts of his <em>Letter to the American people</em> on social media. How TikTok and X, at least for a moment, were rife with people who were barely born when 9/11 happened, proclaiming support for Bin Laden because he had pro-Palestinian things to say. About the importance of digital literacy in the classroom.</li>
  <li>Whenever I’m ill, I bake or cook. I feel bad not doing anything and lying in bed all day, and following a recipe always seems like a good way to pass the time. This week, I made apple crumble custard <em>vlaai</em>. You can take the girl out of Limburg (and thank God for that), but…</li>
</ul>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 09:16:15 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/11/19/week-46</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/11/19/week-46</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Israel-hamas war</category>
        
          <category>Osama bin laden</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The artificial borders of climate activism</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p>Yesterday at the Climate March, someone shouted <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/From_the_river_to_the_sea#Criticism">“From the river to the sea, Palestine will be free”</a>. It was an unfortunate thing. A clean example of the climate changing instantaneously among 85,000 activists.</p>

<p>I was there for four reasons:</p>
<ol>
  <li>My definition of God is “science is indescribably beautiful and we must respect her”</li>
  <li>I can’t think of a more regrettable waste of tax money than having to spend it on health issues we can prevent if only we take better care of our environment</li>
  <li>I have a weak spot for an activist friend, who, through stealth influencing, had instilled in me a deep sense of FOMO about the event</li>
  <li>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carnival_in_the_Netherlands">Dutch carnival season</a> had kicked off on November 11, and I was in the mood for a parade</li>
</ol>

<p>The phrase was understandable coming from the Palestinian woman. Still, I appreciate that its most vicious context of use taints it so ferociously with antisemitism that deploying it as a vehicle for unity is a recipe for disaster. The crowd was so immense that it took hours of dancing in place before we even got started on the route. By the time we got to Museum Square, the words had already left the woman’s mouth.</p>

<p>We got there just in time to watch Greta Thunberg, who had been marching with us, turning her face away from cameras to remind us of why she was there. In between her on the stage and us on the field there were three screens, each projecting her face from a distance. I <em>believe</em> she was there, but the crowd was too big to say anything with much certainty.</p>

<p>My activist friend is one of those rare white people: privileged enough to belong to the 1% of a <em>variety</em> of subgroups, yet so antiracist it brings a tear to your eye. A seeker of nuance and complexity. A political unicorn. As we stood in the longest line I had ever seen, sharing the weight of a “THE CRISIS IS NOW” banner, I said to her: “it’s so… White here.” “Yes,” she said, mildly embarrassed it seemed, “it’s actually a huge problem for us that we could use some help with.”</p>

<p>Growing up in the Dutch South, there was a peculiar detail to the way I engaged with other people of color. I didn’t. There was no nod in the street, no tribe to which I belonged, no “our stories of minority and loneliness resonate”. Color blindness was the tune, and we were dancing to it. After almost a decade in Amsterdam I’ve come to consider this lack of acknowledgement poor behavior. There’s not a black person in the neighborhood I don’t know. I had forgotten my life wasn’t always like this, until yesterday. I counted no more than ten people of color in the crowd, and I exchanged looks with not a single one of them.</p>

<p>Whenever I find myself in a sea of vast whiteness, I ask myself: “where am I, why are there no other people of color here, and should I <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt5052448/"><em>Get Out</em></a>?” Don’t get me wrong, I love white people. <a href="https://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/SomeOfMyBestFriendsAreX">Some of my best friends are white people.</a> My <em>wife</em> is a white person. Consider it a habit I’ve developed growing up in the Netherlands, where nothing about ethnicity is quite as it seems.</p>

<p>What solidifies Greta Thunberg’s identity as a Zoomer is the radical solidarity she and her contemporaries practice, seemingly without effort. Once she finally got on stage, her first act of compassion was to return the word to the Palestinian woman whose sound had been disconnected immediately after she had said the phrase.</p>

<p>What followed is what you may expect to happen when a person traumatized by an active war has to find it in herself to pick up where she left off to tell 85,000 mostly white faces how climate justice and justice for Palestine can exist on the same stage.</p>

<p>It was <em>mayhem</em>.</p>

<p>Once Greta had the mic again, she decided to keep her speech brief, much to the dismay I’m sure of all the people who felt blessed to share a moment in Amsterdam with her. Not <em>so</em> brief, however, that a man couldn’t walk on stage and declare he was there for the climate and not for politics.</p>

<p>The respectability politics are vile today. All I can think about is the power of the speech that could have been. The one in which a Palestinian woman addresses a vast sea of white faces who all listen intently to her talk about climate change. The way she says the words “river” and “sea” only when referring to natural bodies of water. The way she captivates her audience until the very end, when she pulls a Hannah Gadsby to remind us all of the hypocrisy and dangers of compartmental solidarity. The way she nods quietly to the upcoming elections.</p>

<p>The respectability politics are vile today. March-induced feelings of disappointment, uninspired virtue signalling, and racism find each other. A discombobulated display of on-stage pain and the very notion of pro-Palestinian sentiment have quickly been conflated into a rhetoric with which I feel increasingly uncomfortable: that people in power decide when minorities speak about their place in the world. That, when we talk about climate justice, every other topic must give way. That, when we march for a cause that seems to predominantly attract white people, unwritten rules of radical inclusion don’t apply. I feel the climate activism community interviewed for a job with me, and as a result I want to burn its résumé.</p>

<p>It makes me sad.</p>

<p>I’m sad because there are people who think climate justice can exist outside of politics. I’m sad because so many people don’t understand that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_personal_is_political">the personal is political</a>. I’m sad because I want to engage in climate activism, but I don’t feel there’s a place for me at the table. I’m sad because, right now, climate activism feels like a Gutmensch hobby. I’m sad for all the people who can’t tell the difference between antisemitism and anti-Israel sentiment. I’m sad for our Uncle Eli from Tel Aviv who is in and out of his bomb shelter all day.</p>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 09:16:15 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/11/13/artificial-borders-of-climate-activism</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/11/13/artificial-borders-of-climate-activism</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Activism</category>
        
          <category>Climate justice</category>
        
          <category>Israel-hamas war</category>
        
          <category>Intersectionality</category>
        
          <category>Solidarity</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p>Vibing for climate justice with a “Midsommar” umbrella</p>
]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 15:46:50 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/11/12/16-46-gmt-1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/11/12/16-46-gmt-1</guid>
        
          
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>