<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="">
  <channel>
    <title>Zinzy Waleson Geene - RSS</title>
    <description>Zinzy Waleson Geene is a researcher, designer, facilitator, and IndieWeb enthusiast from Amsterdam.</description>
    <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000</link>
    <language></language>
    <copyright>http://0.0.0.0:4000/colophon/#copyright</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>2022 in review</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          Now that we've reached its end, 2022 feels much calmer and steadier than the two previous years. The pandemic, a new job, and major cultural and political developments gave 2020 the rhythm of living in the eye — and sometimes in the fabric — of a hurricane. Made to wear the hand-me-downs of its older brother, 2021 felt much the same. What makes this year different isn't its overall rhythm, but the way it was interrupted.
          
          <br />
          <p>Now that we’ve reached its end, 2022 feels much calmer and steadier than the two previous years. The pandemic, a new job, and major cultural and political developments gave 2020 the rhythm of living in the eye — and sometimes in the fabric — of a hurricane. Made to wear the hand-me-downs of its older brother, 2021 felt much the same. What makes this year different isn’t its overall rhythm, but the way it was interrupted.</p>

<p>My 2022 was all about a pivot I made, inspired by the health consequences I was (or was eventually going to be) experiencing. 2022 was the backdrop of a recovery journey on which I’ve been for a while now. The journey took me to the south of Europe, where, gazing out across the hysterically beautiful lavender-colored valleys of the Algarve, I underwent in-patient treatment for an ongoing eating disorder at <a href="https://humanconcern.nl/">Human Concern</a>.</p>

<p>Here are some things I learned there, and here, in 2022.</p>

<ul class="photo-grid"> 
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295755/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-5_tarer9.jpg" /></li>
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295752/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-1_kogxvz.jpg" /></li>
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295757/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-17_jqkm4r.jpg" /></li>
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295755/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-4_namvxo.jpg" /></li>
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295751/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-2_zynxon.jpg" /></li> 
</ul>

<h3 id="i-finally-found-a-way-to-connect-with-that-intuition-everybody-has-been-raving-about">I finally found a way to connect with that intuition everybody has been raving about.</h3>
<p>I spent my time in the Algarve rigorously slowing and simmering down. Without the usual rush of home life, work, and social engagements distracting me from what’s difficult, I learned to listen to what I deeply know to be true. Entering into that conversation, I’ve become better at noticing what effect everyday life has on me: the “rebound” as we call it in <a class="internal-link" href="/notes/Yin%20yoga/">yin yoga</a>.</p>

<ul class="photo-grid">
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295755/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-9_a74pp8.jpg" /></li> 
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295757/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-21_wghwp1.jpg" /></li> 
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295758/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-20_dcfc7i.jpg" /></li>
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295757/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-18_svuyuq.jpg" /></li>
</ul>

<h3 id="the-design-flaw-that-neurodiversity-isnt">The design flaw that neurodiversity isn’t</h3>
<p>Another transformation this year was kickstarted by Elizabeth Filips, a London medical student and YouTuber who has shown me how I can better organize things and <em>do</em> them.</p>

<p>whose work on productivity has meant wonders for me. All of my life, I’ve been known to learn quickly, think unusually, and get bored easily. (This is why, as I’m writing this, I’m already playing pretty solid Philip Glass on the piano I got a week ago.)</p>

<p>I was never unaware of what this meant or what it’s called, but what I never <em>got</em> was how to work these traits. I always thought I was just bad at consistency, how I was to blame for it, and how I shouldn’t stop trying. I’ve never heard Elizabeth use the word “neurodiversity”, but it’s refreshing to hear from someone with whom I identify so strongly. Thanks to what I learned from her, I’m spending 2022 eagerly embracing my own learning strategies, while optimizing for passion rather than consistency.</p>

<h3 id="it-may-be-valuable-to-jumpstart-a-connection-by-oversharing-but-usually-it-isnt">It may be valuable to jumpstart a connection by oversharing, but usually it isn’t.</h3>
<p>In my treatment cohort were nine other women, each with a uniquely originated eating disorder. Sharing the most difficult things about our lives gave us a non-verbal language that runs on gut feelings, eyes meeting, and quiet hugs.</p>

<p>I have a renewed appreciation for socially pacing myself, though. In 2022, new people came and went, and with the ones who stayed I shared an understanding: you can’t always jumpstart a connection by oversharing, overcommitting, overinvesting. Building relationships takes time, no matter how badly you want to ask a new and exciting person everything about their life.</p>

<p>Lastly, when I do share, I prefer snail mail over quarterly 10-minute voice recording updates over WhatsApp. I spent a portion of 2022 converting the way I keep in touch with people.</p>

<h3 id="surround-yourself-with-worthwhile-stories">Surround yourself with worthwhile stories</h3>
<p>I’ve given up on the need to read all the time. I have a strong confirmation bias for the notion that I don’t read enough, and I’ll see people who are happily devouring books everywhere I turn. Six weeks with no books except a Bible I didn’t touch did wonders for me. The guilt I usually feel over this, especially as a literature graduate, is slowly melting away.</p>

<p>Somehow, 2022 helped me draw another conclusion: life is too short to spend it feeding myself with things that shouldn’t be crowding my mind. It makes it easy to refuse</p>

<ul>
  <li>This is why I won’t be seeing <em><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/12/10/opinion/the-whale-film.html">The Whale</a></em>, and decided that <em>Them</em> wouldn’t be for me either.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="some-other-things-i-learned">Some other things I learned</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Food is cool, but I must chill:</strong> with an eating disorder that masked itself as a snobbish foodie for over a decade, I am wise to be careful when engaging with kitchen projects. After coming back from Portugal, a major shift has been the time I spend in the kitchen. Before I left, I would easily do seven- or ten-hour stints on weekdays<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>. These days, I try to limit myself to an hour, with relative success.</li>
  <li><strong>Dogs aren’t so bad after all:</strong> if you know me in person, one thing you will understand is that, historically, I’m known to hate dogs. Bill Murray once noted that he’s “suspicious of people who don’t like dogs”, and I’ve always proudly countered that with “don’t trust people who are suspicious of people who don’t like dogs”. That being said, 2022 gave me the soft eyes required to decide with Anja that we will be making an effort to welcome a corgi into our home.</li>
  <li></li>
</ul>

<h3 id="8-at-heart-im-a-researcher">8. At heart, I’m a researcher</h3>

<p>One of the main aspects of my professional career has been knowledge work, and while I love nursing the skillset required for that work, I did discover this year that Product Management is not the path for me.</p>

<h3 id="9-eventually-we-become-our-own-perpetrators-its-a-health-hazard">9. Eventually we become our own perpetrators. It’s a <a class="internal-link" href="/notes/Health/">health</a> hazard.</h3>

<ul class="photo-grid">
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295761/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-19_whjyta.jpg" /></li> 
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295758/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-14_kd7qdp.jpg" /></li>  
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295757/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-13_o3demr.jpg" /></li>
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295756/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-22_jtwbwi.jpg" /></li>
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295756/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-23_zffo6i.jpg" /></li> 
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295755/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-9_a74pp8.jpg" /></li> 
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295754/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-10_ydw99a.jpg" /></li>
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295754/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-3_rsacia.jpg" /></li>
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295754/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-24_m4zdhh.jpg" /></li>
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295753/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-8_lotyk1.jpg" /></li>
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295753/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-6_k0s2ef.jpg" /></li>
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295753/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-11_ixyetl.jpg" /></li>
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295753/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-16_z5iwln.jpg" /></li> 
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295752/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-7_uavs9x.jpg" /></li>
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295752/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-12_epttwj.jpg" /></li>  
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295755/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-9_a74pp8.jpg" /></li>
<li><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1672295754/zinzy.website/2022-in-review-15_chnhyh.jpg" /></li> 
</ul>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>Yes, this was during the time I was too sick to work. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=2022%20in%20review">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/12/28/2022-in-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/12/28/2022-in-review</guid>
        
          
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 51: The piano</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          
          
          <br />
          <ul>
  <li>Happy Hanukkah and/or Christmas to those who celebrate!</li>
  <li>Even though our house is (reluctantly) multi-religious, we forgot just about every tradition we were ever taught for this time of the year. On Hanukkah Eve, A. said “where are the tea lights?”, but we had no luck finding them to produce a makeshift chanukiah. Probably for the best. I don’t mind that we didn’t put up a Christmas tree, but I did find myself missing our outrageous ornaments.</li>
  <li>This week was all about the new piano I bought. I can’t stop thinking or talking about it, so for brevity’s sake it’s best you just check out <a class="internal-link" href="/notes/Piano/">my piano journey in my working notes</a>.</li>
  <li>All I’ll say is: this piano project is the first one I’m approaching through a neurodiverse lens, and it’s making everything <em>so</em> much smoother and funner.</li>
  <li>Illegally, I’m mentioning something that happened in week 50. A. took me for my annual Fancy Birthday Dinner. For the first time since we began dating, I told her to leave it a surprise. I suppose it’s one of those benefits of having gone to in-patient eating disorder treatment: chill vibes about food surprises. If you ever have an appetite for exquisite 10-course Asian fusion dining, book a table at <a href="https://101gowrie.com/">101 Gowrie</a>, where the atmosphere is as beautiful as the tableware, the bread is to cry over, and the umami is so intense that you’ll have trouble putting it into words.</li>
  <li>We needed a two-nighter to finish watching <em>Glass Onion: A Knives Out Mystery</em>. I’m very much at that point in my mid-thirties where finishing a feature film under a warm blanket on the sofa after 8 p.m. is a challenge. I love whodunits — the genre might be in my top three — but I was quite disappointed to learn that both A. and I were able to guess the ending within the first five minutes. Janelle Monáe and Kathryn Hahn looked great nonetheless.</li>
  <li>All week, people kept asking me what I’d be doing for Christmas, and I’d cheerfully reply “Nothing! You?” every time. I feel liberated from the pressure to spend time with family or friends during the holidays, to eat more than I can carry, and to <em>be</em> and <em>have</em> fun. We certainly did have fun, just in a “really couldn’t be bothered” kind of way.</li>
  <li>I made my first batch of <a class="internal-link" href="/notes/Heavenly%20mud/">Heavenly mud</a> (“hemelse modder”), a rich, creamy chocolate dessert. It was heavenly.</li>
</ul>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=Week%2051:%20The%20piano">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/12/25/week-51</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/12/25/week-51</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Piano</category>
        
          <category>Music</category>
        
          <category>Learning</category>
        
          <category>Cooking</category>
        
          <category>Holidays</category>
        
          <category>Whodunits</category>
        
          <category>Cinema</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I hate, fear, and suck at</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          A year ago, as part of my recovery journey, my therapist asked me: 'What are your core values? Like, what are your deepest needs and desires?' She reminded me last week that, instead of pausing to think of a response, I laughed straight in her face.
          
          <br />
          <p>A year ago, as part of my <a class="internal-link" href="/notes/eating%20disorder/">recovery journey</a>, my therapist asked me:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>What are your core values? Like, what are your deepest needs and desires?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>She reminded me last week that, instead of pausing to think of a response, I laughed straight in her face.</p>

<p>Historically, I’ve had trouble identifying what I want, need, desire, hope for, and dream of.</p>

<p>In-patient treatment has helped train that muscle, though. My first vision board there consisted of kind interactions with strangers in coffee houses, while other clients were planning to pursue a Master’s or travel the world. On the flight back I made my first-ever attempt at a <a class="internal-link" href="/notes/Bucket%20list/">Bucket list</a>.</p>

<p>Treatment taught me a hack that’s now helping me figure out what I hope 2023 will look like. Instead of identifying what I <em>do</em> hope, want, and yearn for, I look at what I <em>don’t</em>. What I hate can tell me something about what I fear. What I fear can, in turn, lead me to what I desire. Knowing what I suck at can help me identify challenges I might encounter as I move towards those desires.</p>

<p>As the year comes to a close, and as I figure out once again, but now from scratch, <a class="internal-link" href="/notes/How%20I%20Life%20OS/">How I Life OS</a>, I’m asking myself:</p>

<ul>
  <li>What do I hate?</li>
  <li>What do I fear?</li>
  <li>What do I suck at?</li>
</ul>

<p>Rather than seeing my weak points as things I must improve in order to be healthy and happy, I try to figure out how I can use these characteristics to my benefit. I’m looking forward to optimizing <em>for</em> them, so I can have a realistic outlook as I learn and thrive.</p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=What%20I%20hate,%20fear,%20and%20suck%20at">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/12/07/what-i-hate-fear-and-suck-at</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/12/07/what-i-hate-fear-and-suck-at</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Reflection</category>
        
          <category>Life changes</category>
        
          <category>Recovery</category>
        
          <category>Self care</category>
        
          <category>Practices</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 48: Chinese food</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          The week was fairly quiet: I'm still having trouble getting enough rest, which leads to headaches and dizzy spells, but with enough breaks, naps, and beauty sleep I seem to be on a path to feeling better.
          
          <br />
          <ul>
  <li>The week was fairly quiet: I’m still having trouble getting enough rest, which leads to headaches and dizzy spells, but with enough breaks, naps, and beauty sleep I seem to be on a path to feeling better.</li>
  <li>I’m continuing to settle back into work, and I love working on my own design assignment. I can see how much I missed the tangible, practical design work, as well as design collaboration.</li>
  <li>Don’t tell A, but I indulged in a new Filofax setup for 2023. I got my hands on both their <a href="https://uk.filofax.com/collections/a5-refills-for-organisers-and-clipbook/products/minimal-week-to-view-diary-a5-2023">Week on Two Pages Diary</a>, and their <a href="https://uk.filofax.com/products/one-day-on-a-page-diary-with-appointments-a5-2023?_pos=1&amp;_sid=315704f6e&amp;_ss=r">One Day on a Page Diary</a>, to give myself ample space to organize. I’m quite exicted to try the week pages, which have a monthly planner section as well.</li>
  <li>I watched <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Franklin_Delano_Floyd#Death_of_Suzanne_Sevakis">Girl In The Picture</a>, and all I can say is: I have quite the stomach for gruesome stories, but this shook me.</li>
  <li>I also watched <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt11188206/">15 Minutes of Shame</a> and I loved it, particularly the connection they made to medieval punishment. It made me think back to my time as a student, getting acquainted with medieval literature for the first time.</li>
  <li>I had the 👏🏽  best 👏🏽  Chinese 👏🏽  food of my life, at <a href="https://www.hoitin.nl/">Hoi Tin</a>.</li>
</ul>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=Week%2048:%20Chinese%20food">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/12/03/week-48</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/12/03/week-48</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 47: Booster</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          A bit of a dreary week, but at least we have great television.
          
          <br />
          <ul>
  <li>I forgot how the COVID booster can make you feel as though, temporarily, the world may well be ending. I got it earlier this week, and it left me with a sore arm and that dreadful, ridiculous sensation that accompanies a flu that lasts a week too long. I mimic my late stepfather, who used to wimper like a puppy whenever he got a cold.</li>
  <li>I still do well to limit my hours of screen time. Before I know it, I’m stuck with a headache and dizzy spell.</li>
  <li>Spotify’s Discover Weekly was on point this week. Aside from lovely “beards and log cabin” tunes, as I call 70s soft rock, I’ve fallen hard for the hyper pop track <a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/4n0sVfRnd0UJsqcbPj7GqN?si=Z5yeyS2xTjOEWlOSI5EnmQ">“Notice”</a> by Moe Shop and Toriena.</li>
  <li>We raced through another season of <em>The Crown</em>, this time with the excellent Elizabeth Debicki as Diana. I love how she manages to capture Diana so well despite <em>and</em> because of her camp-adjacent interpretation of her. I wonder if she ever got a sore neck during taping.</li>
  <li>After protesting for weeks, I’ve finally let A turn on the heating. So far, I haven’t had much up-close experience with the energy crisis the world is currently facing, and I don’t want that to change. It’s great to feel my toes, though.</li>
</ul>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=Week%2047:%20Booster">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/11/27/week-47</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/11/27/week-47</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Vaccination</category>
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Notes on my web mastery</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          <p>Recently, I’ve been making some great progress with my personal website. While I normally don’t engage in technical ballets on the goings-on of this website, I feel it’s relevant to document what I’ve learnt and done, if only for posterity.</p>

          
          <br />
          <p>Recently, I’ve been making some great progress with my personal website. While I normally don’t engage in technical ballets on the goings-on of this website, I feel it’s relevant to document what I’ve learnt and done, if only for posterity.</p>

<h3 id="tools">Tools</h3>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a>: as is often the case for me, this site is built using my favorite flat-file content management system</li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/">Github</a>: hosts the code for this website</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.netlify.com/">Netlify</a>: serves the content to my website</li>
  <li><a href="https://obsidian.md/">Obsidian</a>: I write in a single Obsidian vault</li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/denolehov/obsidian-git">obsidian-git</a>: helps me manage  the version control of my Obsidian content</li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/marketplace/actions/push-git-subdirectory-as-branch">Push git subdirectory as branch</a>: a Github action that lets me publish a part of the content of my Obsidian vault to a separate repository</li>
  <li><a href="https://mtsknn.fi/blog/netlify-updating-private-git-submodule/">Git submodule</a>: my separate repository is pulled into my website’s code base</li>
  <li><a href="https://mtsknn.fi/blog/how-to-trigger-daily-netlify-builds-using-github-actions/">Netlify build hook</a>: every day, Netlify looks for new content and publishes it to my website</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="why-this-is-great">Why this is great</h3>
<ul>
  <li>I hold the strong belief that &lt;a class=’internal-link’ href=’/notes/<em>%20Tools%20don’t%20matter/’&gt;</em> Tools don’t matter&lt;/a&gt;. This means, among other things, that I don’t like to be limited to using particular platforms or apps to write. I want to see my files in a folder that I can move around. Jekyll allows me to do just this.</li>
  <li>My website is a text-heavy space: most of what you’ll find on here is written content. As a knowledge worker, writing is an integral part of my daily life. Many of the things I write are not for public consumption, but they are closely linked to things that <em>are</em>. To avoid duplicate content and awkward linking, it was important for me to manage my text files in a single space, one Obsidian vault.</li>
  <li>I have a tendency to tinker a lot on my website. This can make it so that I spend more time trying out new things and changing the design than I do writing. Having my code base and content separated helps me focus more on writing things that are meaningful to me.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="some-things-i-havent-figured-out-yet">Some things I haven’t figured out yet</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Is it worthwhile for me to publish more granular IndieWeb post types such as notes and likes? Do I care about them? Am I making them only to show them? What’s their value if I cannot automate this process? Does the technical implementation change if I push said content to a git repository that consists of only notes?</li>
  <li>What does a proper dark mode look like?</li>
  <li>Do I want to continue my barebones experiment and document the <a class="internal-link" href="/notes/Discomfort%20of%20vanity/">Discomfort of vanity</a>? Or am I ready for something more modern?</li>
  <li>How in the world do I even go about Micropub and Webmentions?</li>
</ul>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=Notes%20on%20my%20web%20mastery">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/11/26/notes-on-my-web-mastery</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/11/26/notes-on-my-web-mastery</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Indieweb</category>
        
          <category>Web development</category>
        
          <category>Tinkering</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rest</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          Simmering down is a challenge this week. I wake, daily before 6am, and jump straight into the day.
          
          <br />
          <p>Simmering down is a challenge this week. I wake, daily before 6am, and jump straight into the day. My jump doesn’t land me in a FOMO-inducing Instagram feed or a busy news site, but on a blank screen that waits eagerly as I type my 1,000 words of the morning. It’s another one of the <a class="internal-link" href="/notes/habits/">Habits</a> I picked up this autumn. Me, the darkness outside, and a soft light in the living room acquainting me with the day. It’s pleasing to meet myself, unfiltered.</p>

<p>It’s also one of the few moments of solitude and focus I allow myself this week, apparently. Now that I’m beginning to reintegrate back into work at <span title="There is no note that matches this link." class="invalid-link">  <span class="invalid-link-brackets">[[</span>  Public/_notes/Leeruniek  <span class="invalid-link-brackets">]]</span></span>, I seem to have forgotten how much down time my body still requires. I’ve received a work assignment, on which I’ll get to work independently, and I’m excited. Curious. Hungry. On the cusp of small-scale overdrive. I had to stop working precisely because of this.</p>

<p>It’s boring.</p>

<p>Then I remember and old way to find calm and relaxation. <a href="https://www.iheart.com/podcast/105-stuff-you-should-know-26940277/">The voices of Josh Clark and Chuck Bryant, telling me about stuff I should know</a>.</p>

<h3 id="whats-top-of-mind-right-now">What’s top of mind right now</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Saw Hannah Gadsby’s <a class="internal-link" href="/notes/Body%20of%20Work/">Body of Work</a> and had a brief, cogent crush on her</li>
  <li>Saw a large number of Twitter folks join the much kinder Mastodon club. I’m slowly beginning to feel comfortable about the platform, and how it invites me to share my thoughts.</li>
  <li>I’m thinking a lot about what ex-Twitter designer <a href="https://tech.lgbt/@jon@social.lot23.com/109372263710282940">Jon Bell</a> said about Twitter’s user experience trajectory. I keep saying out loud how central the difference between <a class="internal-link" href="/notes/Do%20the%20right%20thing/">doing the right thing</a> and <a class="internal-link" href="/notes/Do%20the%20thing%20right/">doing the thing right</a> is to the design work I do.</li>
</ul>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=Rest">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/11/20/rest</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/11/20/rest</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 44: Coat</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          <p>The weather has officially reached a temperature that requires me to buy a new coat. I dread it. Unlike most other types of clothing, coats and jackets never seem to suit me, regardless of the style. To soften the blow of having to order several coats on the Internet hoping one will work for me, I granted myself three sets of retro socks.</p>

          
          <br />
          <p>The weather has officially reached a temperature that requires me to buy a new coat. I dread it. Unlike most other types of clothing, coats and jackets never seem to suit me, regardless of the style. To soften the blow of having to order several coats on the Internet hoping one will work for me, I granted myself three sets of retro socks.</p>

<p>I finished reading <a class="internal-link" href="/notes/The%20Midnight%20Library/">The Midnight Library</a>, which I had borrowed from <a href="https://www.anneliewambeek.com/">Annelie</a>. It sure has been a long time since I last read a book that was both so entertaining and easygoing. It feels borderline young adult, and entirely unpretentious.</p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=Week%2044:%20Coat">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/11/06/week-44</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/11/06/week-44</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Reading</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 16: Springtime holidays</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          <p>Each year I’m less embarrassed to say it: I don’t like that stretch of time during the Dutch Springtime when no work week is normal. Aside from the usual Christian holidays there’s King’s Day and Liberation Day, and I’ve found it really messes with my head. I don’t mind them much looking ahead (like I did last week, but having to live through it could well be too much for me.</p>

          
          <br />
          <p>Each year I’m less embarrassed to say it: I don’t like that stretch of time during the Dutch Springtime when no work week is normal. Aside from the usual Christian holidays there’s King’s Day and Liberation Day, and I’ve found it really messes with my head. I don’t mind them much looking ahead (like I did last week, but having to live through it could well be too much for me.</p>

<p>This week, I learn that bolognese is a great base for chili, as long as you add enough cumin, beef, and beer. We watch <em>The Undoing</em>, which is a surprisingly great decision of Hugh Grant.</p>


          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=Week%2016:%20Springtime%20holidays">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/04/23/week-16</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/04/23/week-16</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Television</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 15: Ironic</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          
          <p>Brushing my teeth on Friday morning, I think about the weekend ahead, secretly complaining that my social engagements will keep me from getting the rest I need. Then I remember Easter Monday. The true marker of my mid-thirties is the excitement I feel at the prospect of a bed, and nothing but it.</p>

          
          <br />
          <p>Brushing my teeth on Friday morning, I think about the weekend ahead, secretly complaining that my social engagements will keep me from getting the rest I need. Then I remember Easter Monday. The true marker of my mid-thirties is the excitement I feel at the prospect of a bed, and nothing but it.</p>

<p>I hold a baby this week, one of my favorite ones. His face has two states that exist simultaneously: the one of utter shock and surprise only newborns can have, and the one that reminds you that babies know <em>everything</em> about the world and forget it as soon as they start to speak. He laughs when I bop his nose, although I quickly learn that the force with which I bop Anja’s adult nose shan’t be applied here.</p>

<p>There’s a French bakery in Amsterdam that I visit on Wednesday with my colleague Ruby. Since their actual oven is somewhere else, I wonder if the shop even calls itself a bakery. After all, French standards would forbid it. The caramel éclair reminds me of that time at <a href="https://www.un-dimanche-a-paris.com/">Un Dimanche à Paris</a>, a high I’ve been chasing since mid-2018. The bread has been in the window too long. I ask if they have plastic bags, and I’m told no. I say I think that should be illegal in bakeries.</p>

<p>My childhood friend Mathilde comes for dinner on Sunday. Anja and I are giddy with excitement. In preparation, we practice our harmonies to Alanis Morissette’s “Ironic”over voice messages. Her husband asks her if she, too, heard the cat meowing. We’re celebrating her birthday, and I got her gifts at <a href="http://www.javabookshop.nl/">Java Bookshop</a>. When I ask them about the East-Asian gay guy who writes letters to his mom, they immediately give me Ocean Vuong’s new book of poetry. Seeing her again, I better understand what It means to have a soulmate. I sing so loud I give myself a migraine. It’s worth it.</p>

<p>It took a while before I settled into a suitable solution for the way I produce content on this website. I write Markdown, and had set up <a href="https://mdxjs.com/">mdx</a> in case I ever needed some more complexity in my content files. I would mostly update content through my desktop client, but have <a href="https://workingcopyapp.com/">Working Copy</a> for iOS installed, which I enjoy as much as anyone could enjoy a touchscreen Git client. I was missing some functionalities that are natural to the way I generally write, and so I decided to move my content into an Obsidian vault. I could make a spiel about how I love the “slow web”-ness of writing things on my phone and only publishing them when I’m on my computer, but I simply haven’t figured out how to do it any other way.</p>

          <hr /><p><a href="mailto:?subject=Week%2015:%20Ironic">Reply via email</a></p>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/04/17/week-15</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/04/17/week-15</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Babies</category>
        
          <category>Food</category>
        
          <category>Friends</category>
        
          <category>Web development</category>
        
          <category>Indieweb</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>