<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="">
  <channel>
    <title>Zinzy Waleson Geene - RSS</title>
    <description>A researcher, designer, mentor, queer facilitator, and IndieWeb enthusiast from Amsterdam.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <language></language>
    <copyright>http://localhost:4000/colophon/#copyright</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>Dear Nienke, you should have a website</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<p>Every time I embark on a journey towards a published post about why it’s good to have a website, I get lost in the reality of personal details. Everyone has different reasons for believing something. Aiming to take them all into account doesn’t help me write anything that feels worthwhile and not like a derivative<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>.</p>

<p>It feels much more relevant to focus my attention on specific people. In this case I’m focusing my attention on you, Nienke. I think you should have a personal website. Let me tell you why.</p>

<p>You should have a personal website not because you need to grow an audience, and turn your hobbyist writing into a profession.</p>

<p>You should have a personal website not because you’re an expert on some subject, and it would be cruel to deny the world your wisdom.</p>

<p>You should have a personal website not because you think you’re important.</p>

<p>You should have a personal website not because the world is in need of your highlight reel.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>You should have a personal website because I think the online world is as real as the offline world. You have a presence in one, and you should have a presence in the other.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Consider your personal website an online living room of sorts. The place that displays, in a variety of ways, who you are, what you care about, and how you’re moving through the world.</p>

<p>You’re free to invite anyone to come in, and have them see anything you deem relevant. They can stay for three seconds and walk out the door, or dwell for a bit, opening drawers, going back in time, answering questions, questioning answers.</p>

<p>Imagine that there are people on the other side of the world who would want to know how you’re doing, what you’re thinking and learning. Not because you’re you, per se, but simply because you have in common the habit of sharing your experiences in an online space where you are the boss.</p>

<p>There is a <em>cozy web</em> out there, where people connect simply because they enjoy snacking on each other’s slices of life: the seemingly unimportant moments, words, images that approximate what it means to be human.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Imagine, also, what it means when I say “you are the boss”.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Think of how little you control about yourself on the Internet. The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">.nl</code> website of your name is already registered, but are you its owner? I doubt it. Your company has a portrait of you on their website, and it’s beautiful, but you can’t add anything to the page it’s on, can you?</p>

<p>You have an updated LinkedIn page and it’s a great way for people to find you, but do you live to work or work to live? Besides, it’s LinkedIn designers who decide for you what your profile will look like. If you’d ever want to do anything other than write a post or update your experiences, you’re out of luck.</p>

<p>There’s an old newsletter containing an interview with you, again with that wonderful portrait. It’s probably because of your work that this is all I can find on you. It makes me sad, Nienke, it does.</p>

<p>You know why? I love learning about what you’re up to. And I suspect the places where you share that are social media profiles that don’t necessarily use your full name. It’s great for privacy, of course, I get it. But I don’t want to be on social media to stay in your loop.</p>

<p>Or rather, I want social media to be our websites. You read mine and I read yours, we write comments on our own websites and they’re posted to each other’s websites automatically.<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> Twitter can fall, Instagram can crumble, LinkedIn can add an expensive subscription model, but you and I will still have our websites.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I want you to take up space on the Internet, Nienke.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I want you to enjoy doing so and perhaps even making new connections in the process. I want you to learn how to build your own website and tell me in a year that it’s actually much easier than you thought. I want you to feel empowered. And to have a <a href="/now" target="_blank">now</a> page, and to keep lists on your websites of things you love in Amsterdam and beyond.</p>

<p>I want you to feel that you can escape the rat race of likes, favs, and reposts. I think what you have to say is worth more than the hipness of some platform.</p>

<p>I want you to fall in love with personal websites so much that you write about it on your website, and tell people about it at Coffee Company.</p>

<p>I want to share with you the wonderful community of random people from all over the world, who are so much more curious and enthusiastic, so genuinely supportive, and so much kinder than any of the communities I’ve ever found on Big Tech platforms.</p>

<p>I want to read what you have to say about the world when you stop worrying what your blog should be called.</p>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>See for example <a href="https://jamesg.blog/2023/04/13/exploring-personal-websites/" target="_blank">James’ neat post on personal sites</a> or, more broadly, <a href="https://indieweb.org/why" target="_blank">the “Why” page on the IndieWeb Wiki</a> <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>On the IndieWeb we call this a <a href="https://indieweb.org/Webmention" target="_blank">“webmention”</a>. <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/26/dear-nienke-you-should-have-a-website/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/04/26/dear-nienke-you-should-have-a-website/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Friends</category>
        
          <category>Indieweb</category>
        
          <category>Personal archiving</category>
        
          <category>Letters</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Maker's marks for King's Day</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<p>It’s late in the morning and I’m on my way to Gerimedica, the company’s I’m excited to be joining in May, which is next week already. I’m on my bike listening to an American podcast about the history of Dutch anarchist cycling culture.<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> The scene could only be more Dutch if I had a frying pan with bitterballen on the back of my bike.</p>

<p>The commute is wonderful: it takes me from the East side of Amsterdam via De Pijp and Vondelpark to perhaps the most beautiful building I’ve ever had the privilege of calling my office. I cross the river Amstel, enjoy the sun, and marvel at the preparations people have been making.</p>

<p>In two days, King’s Day is upon us. It’s always a big event in the country, and specifically in Amsterdam, and this year it’s extra special: our king was coronated ten years ago this year. In our house it’s not a big deal, in fact Anja couldn’t be more of an anti-monarchist if she tried. Lemonade’s too young to pay it any mind, I’m sure. But the rest of the country is getting ready.</p>

<p>King’s Day is full of traditions: young children playing the violin out of tune at the park, tompouce pastries, the king and his family on a heavily-televised trip to a Dutch city that has been preparing for this moment for a year. And forever and for always: people securing a spot on the flea market route days ahead of time.</p>

<p>Today, as I biked across the city, I saw hundreds of them; 40 square feet of pavement taped off by people aiming to use that specific spot to spend their King’s Day. Peddling by, I thought to myself that it was a rather sweet unwritten rule: I put my name here in a manner that you could erase at any moment, but Dutch custom says you’re to honor my plan.</p>

<p>I’m used to people marking these spots “bezet” (“taken”) or adding their name for emphasis. Today, however, I noticed many people had made a small figure with their tape, a maker’s mark of sorts. I’m learning through Anja’s ceramics adventure that this is entirely common in the potter community: a small, minimalist figure telling the world you made something.</p>

<p>I hope all those people get what they came for: that specific spot on the pavement, and a fun day to help them Konmari their house. In the meantime, I also hope that the Amsterdamse Bos is quiet on King’s Day. I’m looking to take Anja and Lemonade there for a quiet afternoon, far away from the crowds.</p>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>I’m referring to the episode <a href="https://99percentinvisible.org/episode/de-fiets-is-niets/" target="_blank">“De fiets is niets”</a> (“the bike is nothing”) of the impeccable podcast <em>99% Invisible</em> by Roman Mars. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/25/makers-marks-for-kings-day/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/04/25/makers-marks-for-kings-day/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Neighborhood</category>
        
          <category>Funny</category>
        
          <category>Language</category>
        
          <category>Park</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Come back to Chigaco</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<p>Spring is here, I think? I spend the afternoon in the park with ex-colleague-turned-friend Susan, who is celebrating landing a new and challenging job. There’s a boy in the park who’s walking around barefoot. Later we see him on a slack line. I like this scene; it tells me that summer is almost upon us.</p>

<p>I never seem skilled at enjoying whatever season is here. Instead I’m forever yearning for what’s just out of reach. On Javastraat I pass a travel agency, the target audience of which most certainly is concerned with visiting Morocco or Turkey during the summer months. Surprisingly, there’s a wide array of names that would inspire city trips around the world.</p>

<p>Ever since I passed the agency, Andrew Bird’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oecHq2neweA" target="_blank">Pulaski at Night</a> has been in my head non-stop. “Come back to Chigaco, city of, city of light.”</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/17/come-back-to-chigaco/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/04/17/come-back-to-chigaco/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Neighborhood</category>
        
          <category>Funny</category>
        
          <category>Language</category>
        
          <category>Park</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anja's ceramics course</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<p>Today, Lemonade and I visited <a href="https://www.studiopansa.com/studio-pansa-amstel" target="_blank">Studio Pansa Amstel</a>, where Anja has spent the last seven Sundays learning how to work a ceramics wheel. It’s quite the adventure for her, and I love seeing her dive into a new field that’s so different from her day-to-day life and work. Their motto is “dirty hands, clear mind”, and that certainly seems to be the case for Anja.</p>

<p>I saw dozens of gorgeous little cups in the making, each with a unique maker’s mark and the intricate details only found in things that were crafted by hands. I think I’ll sign up for one of Pansa’s courses myself some day.</p>

<div class="breakout">
    <div class="breakout-content">
        <img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/v1681746974/2023-04-16_1_btgjvq.jpg" alt="" class="mb-5">
        <img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/v1681746974/2023-04-16_5_m7uc31.jpg" alt="" class="mb-5">
        <img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dbi2zounq/image/upload/v1681746974/2023-04-16_2_k1jgtv.jpg" alt="" class="mb-5">
    </div>
</div>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/16/anjas-ceramics-course/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/04/16/anjas-ceramics-course/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Anja</category>
        
          <category>Hobbies</category>
        
          <category>Ceramics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meeting Yana and DJ</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<p>What I love most about today’s snapshot is the despair I can see in Lemonade’s eyes even when her entire body is a background blur. DJ is a calm 12-year-old dog, and Lemonade was thrilled to see another dog in our home for the first time, but her energy level was high enough that I eventually brought her back to her crate. It was right in time, too, because the afternoon light filling the living room made for a nice little portrait.</p>

<p>It was wonderful to welcome Yana into our home for the first time. When I hired her in the late Winter of 2022 as our newest UX designer, I knew there was something special about her. Now, well over a year later, I’m pleased to call her a friend. We caught up on career adventures, new trends in the design industry, and of course the joys of being a dog mom.</p>

<p>After Yana and DJ left, Anja and I began winding down for the day. After dinner, we watched the latest episode of the final season of <em>Succession</em>, which may have been my favorite one yet. The characters on this show are so complex and candidly-written. I’m already low-key heartbroken that this show is going to end. At the same time, I’m also pleased to be alive to watch it unfold in real time.</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/11/meeting-yana-and-dj/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/04/11/meeting-yana-and-dj/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Pets</category>
        
          <category>Neighborhood</category>
        
          <category>Friends</category>
        
          <category>Dogs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The cat</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<p>Life sure is different now that we’ve gotten Lemonade on a proper walking schedule. She still feels most comfortable going potty on the puppy pads we have on our balcony, but she absolutely loves going out and exploring the neighborhood.</p>

<p>I’m surprised by how well she walks on a loose leash, and how few issues we’ve had with the stuff she puts in her mouth. I’m hoping to make most use of her imprint period, and that means familiarizing her with as many different things as possible.</p>

<p>I’m happy to find a cat on our morning walk. Lemonade responds to the cat the way I expected a dog would: oozing deference. They stand across from each other for a few minutes, and I reward Lemonade with cheese treats afterwards.</p>

<p>It’s the first step on the road to Lemonade meeting Pookie, my mother-in-law’s cat.</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/10/the-cat/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/04/10/the-cat/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Pets</category>
        
          <category>Neighborhood</category>
        
          <category>Cats</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eight of ten</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<p>When I first set foot in the <a href="https://amsterdam.oudkatholiek.nl/" target="_blank">Old Catholic Church</a> to attend an All Saints service, <a href="/2023/02/12/all-saints-amsterdam/" target="_blank">I knew I had found a special place</a>. Today is the third time I make it to their service, which is always on the second Sunday of the month.</p>

<p>It just so happens that this second Sunday falls on Easter, and it’s perhaps because of this that the service is more crowded than previous times. I see All Saints regulars as well as new people, shy and seemingly hopeful.</p>

<p>One woman in particular stands out to me because she smiles intently at me a few times. She has the demeanor of that good Christian girl from that <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/DunderMifflin/comments/hqskev/scotts_tots_may_be_super_cringe_but_its_nearly/" target="_blank"><em>Office US</em> episode “Christening”</a>.</p>

<p>After service she finds me immediately: “You’re Zinzy from <a href="https://meetup.com/queersalon" target="_blank">Queer Salon</a>, right?” Annika says. Pre-pandemic memories begin to surface, and once she mentions her son I remember her again. “The first time I came here, I thought of you”, she says. We shmooze over crackers and sweet bread, exchange numbers to set a coffee date.</p>

<p>This new church is really a pilot by two reverends hoping to bring fully inclusive Christianity to the Amsterdam expat community. This is service eight out of ten. When I say that out loud, Reverend Howie casually says “yes, we’ll have to talk about that next time.”</p>

<p>I already can’t imagine myself without this community.</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/09/eight-of-ten/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/04/09/eight-of-ten/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Religion</category>
        
          <category>Amsterdam</category>
        
          <category>Queerdom</category>
        
          <category>Queer salon</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A very Mathilde visit</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<p>Much like last year, I’m so excited for Mathilde to visit our house that I get a headache just thinking about it. We’ve known each other 23 years, and, by miracle, our friendship is both acclimatized to our adult lives <em>and</em> as full of energy and curiosity as it was when we met in our first year of secondary school.</p>

<p>She comes bearing gifts: seeds for the garden, dyke poetry, David Sedaris. She knows what I like. We eat, this time around I’ve kept it simple with dishes from the traiteur and not ten separate homemade recipes of intricate delicacies. We talk about what teaching means to her and Anja. We play with Lemonade.</p>

<p>As a friend, Mathilde is very easy to love. Our times together eventually always bring us back to our shared emotional outlet: making music. “I’m nervous to sing around you, Zinzy” she says, but her voice sounds beautiful, warm, and exactly what my piano calls for. When I think of “blue-eyed soul” I think of Mathilde’s voice. We tell each other Anja and I will make it down south this year, and we’ll go for côte de bœuf in Maastricht. I can’t wait.</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/08/a-very-mathilde-visit/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/04/08/a-very-mathilde-visit/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Friends</category>
        
          <category>Pets</category>
        
          <category>Weekends</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Showing up not knowing what will happen</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<p>I met Shervin at the coffee place this morning. We know each other very casually; we used to frequent the same co-working space, we’re LinkedIn friends. He has one of those faces that you just want to meet with a smile.</p>

<p>We exchange how life is treating us, what we’re doing at work. He tells me about his side projects, and how one of them is an invite-only meetup where you attend without knowing what you’ll be doing. He lets me in on secrets around the next meetup, and tells me what kind of activities are involved. It sounds magical.</p>

<p>There’s beauty in the not knowing, we agree. In the whimsy of the unexpected, the sudden connection we may feel with other humans. I tell him his project reminds me of Marina Abramović, whom Anja and I were fortunate enough to meditate with <a href="https://carre.nl/pagina/marina-in-carre" target="_blank">in Carre last year</a>. Participating in <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2010/04/04/nyregion/04about.html" target="_blank">her famous eye-gazing practice</a> with complete strangers was transformative.</p>

<p>I’m glad I got an invitation.</p>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/04/01/showing-up-not-knowing-what-will-happen/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/04/01/showing-up-not-knowing-what-will-happen/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Coffee place</category>
        
          <category>Performance art</category>
        
          <category>Meetups</category>
        
          <category>Whimsy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 11: Meeting Patrick</title>
        <author> ()</author>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <html><body>
<ul>
  <li>I got to meet one of my Internet heroes this week: <a href="patrickrhone.com" target="_blank">Patrick Rhone</a> and his family were on a Europe trip, and I was lucky enough <a href="https://www.patrickrhone.net/13189-2/" target="_blank">to catch the planning stage on his blog</a> right in time to extend an invitation. We spent a rainy Monday evening in de Jordaan at <a href="http://www.cafedetuin.nl/" target="_blank">Cafe de Tuin</a>, talking ye olde Internet productivity culture, the arts, politics, hopes and dreams, and how his teenage daughter apparently woke up one night singing “raise a glass to freedom”. Fine people, they are.</li>
  <li>After another week with Lemonade, I’m beginning to feel more confident about raising her to be a well-behaved, confident puppy. For the most part, she’s doing very well. The only real challenge we have is the barking to which she’ll resort every time she’s in the crate but not sleeping. Through trial and error, we’re slowly learning how to help her settle down more easily, and this week, the efforts have begun to pay off.</li>
  <li>I’ve got some exciting news forthcoming that isn’t quite ready for the public just yet, but it has managed to lift my spirits greatly. I’ll be able to write more in the next few weeks, but for now it’s safe to say I’m feeling hopeful, inspired, and ready.</li>
  <li>While Anja had apparently been around to watch season one when it was released, I’ve only now turned onto the wonderful journey that is <em>Abbott Elementary</em>. I would never actually ask the universe for a reboot of <em>The Office: US</em>, but this new mockumentary revolving around a poorly-managed, underfunded Philadelphia public school has exactly the vibe I would’ve hoped to get from that nonexistent reboot. It’s just nice that, with this show, Black people are at the front and center.</li>
  <li>Spring has officially begun, but as one of the regulars at my coffee place said: “the question isn’t when spring begins but when  rain ends”. It seems the weather’s getting better, though, and I can feel I’m on the cusp of storing away my winter coat. It has been a long time coming.</li>
</ul>
</body></html>]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/03/26/week-11/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/03/26/week-11/</guid>
        
          
        
        
          <category>Weeknotes</category>
        
          <category>Internet friends</category>
        
          <category>Lemonade</category>
        
          <category>Pets</category>
        
          <category>Television</category>
        
          <category>Spring</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>